<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Polkadot Ecosystem | Notícias</title><description/><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/</link><language>pt</language><item><title>Approval-Based Committee Voting on the Polkadot Blockchain</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/approval-based-committee-voting-on-the-polkadot-blockchain/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/approval-based-committee-voting-on-the-polkadot-blockchain/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;import { ShowcaseTwitter } from &amp;#39;starlight-showcases&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from institutions like Harvard University, the University of Warwick, and the Web3 Foundation delved into the world of blockchain governance through the lens of the Polkadot blockchain. This exploration sheds light on approval-based committee elections, a cornerstone of the Nominated Proof-of-Stake mechanism vital for blockchain security and representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Essence of the Study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot blockchain serves as a living laboratory for examining approval-based committee (ABC) voting, where around one thousand candidates vie for approval from tens of thousands of weighted voters. The study not only quantifies the outcomes of different voting rules but also introduces a novel perspective on overrepresentation—a critical factor for the blockchain’s security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Key Findings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-World Data Collection&lt;/strong&gt;: This research stands out by compiling 496 real-world ABC elections from the Polkadot blockchain, revealing a detailed landscape of voter and candidate dynamics over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-Depth Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: A meticulous comparison of voting rules highlights the nuances of voter representation and the potential for overrepresentation. Remarkably, the study pioneers quantitative measures for over- and underrepresentation, offering a new toolkit for evaluating voting rules on real-world data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: The findings have profound implications for blockchain security, particularly in preventing overrepresentation that could compromise the network. The study’s insights advocate for more sophisticated, proportional voting rules, akin to those used by Polkadot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research not only advances our understanding of ABC voting but also provides actionable insights for blockchain developers and stakeholders. By evaluating the impact of committee size and the possibility of selecting multiple copies of candidates, the study offers recommendations that could enhance both representation and security in blockchain governance.&lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;ShowcaseTwitter
  entries={[
    &amp;#39;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BillLaboon/status/1777604794485453254&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/BillLaboon/status/1777604794485453254&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;,
  ]}
/&amp;gt;
This groundbreaking study bridges theoretical voting mechanisms and practical application within the burgeoning field of blockchain technology. By dissecting the intricacies of approval-based committee voting on the Polkadot network, it illuminates the path toward more secure, representative, and efficient blockchain systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://ojs.aaai.org/index.php/AAAI/article/view/28807&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Approval-Based Committee Voting in Practice: A Case Study of (over-)Representation in the Polkadot Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Governance</category><category>DAO</category></item><item><title>Cardano Partnerchain Framework Built on Substrate!</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/cardano-partnerchain-framework-built-on-substrate/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/cardano-partnerchain-framework-built-on-substrate/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The blockchain landscape is constantly evolving, with new technologies and frameworks emerging to address the growing demands for scalability, security, and interoperability. One of the most significant developments in this space is the &lt;strong&gt;integration of Substrate, the modular blockchain framework developed by Parity Technologies, into the Cardano ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;. This article explores the significance of the Cardano chain built on Substrate, highlighting its potential impact on the broader blockchain ecosystem and the synergies between Cardano and Polkadot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Substrate Framework?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substrate is a highly customizable and modular framework designed to facilitate the creation of purpose-built blockchains. &lt;strong&gt;Developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/parity-technologies/&quot;&gt;Parity Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, Substrate provides developers with the tools and flexibility to create blockchains tailored to specific use cases without the need to build from scratch&lt;/strong&gt;. Its modularity allows for the integration of various consensus mechanisms, governance models, and runtime environments, making it an ideal choice for projects looking to innovate in the blockchain space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cardano’s Adoption of Substrate: A Strategic Move&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision by &lt;strong&gt;IOHK&lt;/strong&gt;, one of Cardano’s founding entities, to &lt;strong&gt;build the Cardano Partnerchain on Substrate&lt;/strong&gt; marks a significant milestone in the evolution of both the Cardano and Polkadot ecosystems. Released on August 1st, 2024, the Cardano Partnerchain v1.0.0 represents the first instance of Cardano leveraging Substrate to enhance its blockchain infrastructure. This move is not only a testament to the versatility of Substrate but also a strategic decision that underscores the growing importance of interoperability and cross-chain collaboration in the blockchain industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cardano Partnerchain Key Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cardano Partnerchain v1.0.0 release includes two primary components: the &lt;code&gt;partner-chains-node&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;partner-chains-cli&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;partner-chains-node&lt;/code&gt; is a Substrate-based node binary specifically tailored for operating Cardano partner chains, while the &lt;code&gt;partner-chains-cli&lt;/code&gt; is a command-line interface wizard designed to simplify the configuration and management of these chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release is compatible with various Cardano tools and components, including smart contracts, the Cardano node, and the Cardano DB Sync. The integration of Substrate into the Cardano ecosystem allows for greater flexibility in deploying and managing partner chains, paving the way for more innovative use cases and applications within the Cardano network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enhancing Interoperability Between Polkadot and Cardano&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting aspects of Cardano’s adoption of Substrate is the potential for &lt;strong&gt;enhanced interoperability between the Cardano and Polkadot ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/cardano-polkadot-bridge-bridging-two-powerhouses-of-blockchain/&quot;&gt; See Polkadot &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Cardano Bridge&lt;/a&gt;. Polkadot, known for its relay chain and parachain architecture, has always emphasized the importance of cross-chain communication and interoperability. By building on Substrate, Cardano can leverage Polkadot’s interoperability features, enabling seamless communication and data transfer between Cardano-based chains and other Substrate-based blockchains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This development also highlights the synergies between the Cardano and Polkadot ecosystems, particularly in their approach to governance and consensus mechanisms. Both ecosystems utilize a combination of Proof of Stake (PoS) and liquid democracy, allowing for more flexible and decentralized governance structures. The integration of Substrate into Cardano could lead to further collaboration between the two ecosystems, fostering innovation and the development of new blockchain applications that benefit from the strengths of both networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of Substrate in Expanding the Cardano Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of Substrate into the Cardano ecosystem is expected to play a crucial role in expanding the network’s capabilities and use cases. &lt;strong&gt;By utilizing Substrate, Cardano can more easily develop and deploy specialized blockchains, or “&lt;em&gt;partner chains&lt;/em&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;, tailored to specific industries or applications. This modular approach allows for greater flexibility in designing blockchain solutions that meet the unique needs of various sectors, from finance and supply chain management to decentralized finance (DeFi) and non-fungible tokens (NFTs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the ability to create and manage multiple partner chains within the Cardano ecosystem enhances the network’s scalability and resilience. As more partner chains are developed and integrated into the Cardano network, the overall capacity of the ecosystem to handle a diverse range of applications and use cases will increase, positioning Cardano as a leading blockchain platform in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cardano Potential Challenges and Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the integration of Substrate into the Cardano ecosystem offers numerous benefits, it also presents several challenges that must be addressed. One of the primary concerns is the complexity of managing multiple partner chains within the Cardano network. As the number of partner chains grows, so too does the potential for network congestion and security vulnerabilities. To mitigate these risks, it will be essential for Cardano to implement robust governance and security mechanisms that can effectively manage the increased complexity of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consideration is the potential for fragmentation within the Cardano ecosystem as more specialized partner chains are developed. While the modularity of Substrate allows for the creation of highly customized blockchains, it also increases the likelihood of fragmentation, where different partner chains may become isolated from one another. To address this issue, Cardano will need to prioritize interoperability and cross-chain communication between its partner chains, ensuring that the ecosystem remains cohesive and interconnected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Future of Cardano on Substrate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to build the Cardano Partnerchain on Substrate represents a bold step forward for the Cardano ecosystem and a significant validation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/tech-talks/substrate-the-future-proof-blockchain-framework-sub0-2024/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Substrate framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As the blockchain industry continues to evolve, the ability to create and manage specialized blockchains that can seamlessly interact with one another will become increasingly important. By leveraging Substrate, Cardano is positioning itself at the forefront of this trend, &lt;strong&gt;paving the way for a new era of interoperability, innovation, and collaboration in the blockchain space&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, the continued development and refinement of the Cardano Partnerchain will be critical to the success of this initiative. As more projects and developers begin to explore the possibilities offered by Substrate, the Cardano ecosystem will likely see an influx of new ideas, applications, and partnerships. This, in turn, will drive further innovation and growth, solidifying Cardano’s position as a leading blockchain platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the integration of Substrate into the Cardano ecosystem marks a significant milestone in the evolution of blockchain technology and interoperability capabilities with the Polkadot ecosystem. By building on Substrate, Cardano is not only enhancing its own capabilities but also contributing to the broader blockchain ecosystem’s growth and development. As Cardano continues to explore the potential of Substrate, the possibilities for innovation and collaboration within the blockchain industry are virtually limitless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/cardano-partnerchain-v1-release-built-on-substrate/9548&quot;&gt;Keep reading the topic at the Polkadot Forum.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Cardano &lt;&gt; Polkadot Blockchains Bridge</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/cardano-polkadot-bridge-bridging-two-powerhouses-of-blockchain/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/cardano-polkadot-bridge-bridging-two-powerhouses-of-blockchain/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge&lt;/strong&gt; represents a step forward in achieving a connected web3 industry, linking two of the most innovative blockchain ecosystems in a way that could reshape the landscape of decentralized finance (DeFi), non-fungible tokens (NFTs), and beyond. This article delves into the technical challenges, potential solutions, and the broader implications of &lt;strong&gt;building a bridge between Cardano and Polkadot&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction to Cardano and Polkadot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardano and Polkadot are among the top blockchain platforms, both designed to provide scalable and secure environments for decentralized applications (dApps). Cardano, created by Charles Hoskinson, known for its rigorous peer-reviewed research and layered architecture, aims to offer a sustainable and scalable blockchain. On the other hand, Polkadot, initially developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/parity-technologies/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parity Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/web3-foundation/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3 Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, led by figures such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/gavin-wood/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gavin Wood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and now managed in a completely decentralized way by the community of token holders, focuses on i&lt;strong&gt;nteroperability and scalability&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling different blockchains (parachains) to transfer messages and data seamlessly across its network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Blockchain Interoperability Matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interoperability between blockchains like Cardano and Polkadot is critical for fostering a more &lt;strong&gt;connected and user-friendly decentralized ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;. As the blockchain industry grows, the need for different networks to communicate with each other becomes increasingly important. This cross-chain interaction can unlock new use cases, reduce friction for users, and enable a more integrated and robust Web3 environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Challenges of the Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a bridge between two distinct blockchain platforms is no small feat. The Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge project faces several technical challenges, each requiring careful consideration and innovative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consensus Mechanism Differences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the primary challenges lies in the differences between &lt;strong&gt;Cardano’s Ouroboros consensus&lt;/strong&gt; protocol and &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s Nominated Proof-of-Stake (NPoS) mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;. Ouroboros, a proof-of-stake protocol, emphasizes security and energy efficiency, while Polkadot’s NPoS focuses on scalability and interoperability through its relay chain and parachain architecture. Bridging these two consensus mechanisms requires creating a &lt;strong&gt;system that can understand and validate the distinct blocks and signatures generated by each protocol&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finality and Transaction Speed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another significant challenge is ensuring transaction finality and speed. Cardano transactions typically achieve finality after a set number of confirmations. Polkadot, through its &lt;strong&gt;BABE&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;GRANDPA&lt;/strong&gt; consensus algorithms, offers a different approach to finality. Synchronizing these two systems to achieve efficient cross-chain transactions without compromising on security is a complex task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Light Client Implementation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/guides/introduction-to-polkadot-light-clients-guide/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;light client&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—a simplified node that can interact with a full blockchain node without needing to download the entire blockchain—is central to the Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge. The light client must be able to verify transactions on both networks, ensuring that they meet the required consensus rules of each blockchain. This requires deep integration and understanding of both ecosystem’s cryptographic protocols and data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proposed Solutions and Developments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these challenges, several solutions have been proposed to facilitate the &lt;strong&gt;Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge&lt;/strong&gt;. These solutions involve leveraging existing technologies within both ecosystems and innovating where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Using Mithril for Cardano Verification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mithril&lt;/strong&gt;, a research project by the Cardano Foundation, offers &lt;strong&gt;a potential solution for verifying Cardano transactions on the Polkadot network&lt;/strong&gt;. Mithril provides stake-based threshold multisignatures, which allow a subset of Cardano validators to opt-in and provide signatures. This light client protocol could potentially reduce the time required for transaction finality, making the bridge more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Employing BEEFY for Polkadot Verification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Polkadot to Cardano direction, the use of &lt;strong&gt;BEEFY (Bridge Enhanced Efficiency Finality Yield)&lt;/strong&gt; proofs is proposed. BEEFY is a specialized consensus protocol designed by Polkadot to facilitate interoperability with other blockchains. It simplifies the export of validator set changes, enabling other chains, like Cardano, to verify Polkadot’s state with high efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Combining Sampling and SNARKs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridge could also explore combining sampling-based approaches with succinct non-interactive arguments of knowledge (&lt;strong&gt;SNARKs&lt;/strong&gt;) for enhanced security and efficiency. While Cardano’s current elliptic curve support limits the direct use of SNARKs, future updates could enable more advanced cryptographic techniques, further strengthening the bridge’s security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Central Node for Consensus Mechanism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another innovative solution proposed within the community is the &lt;strong&gt;use of a central node or gear that interacts between both blockchains&lt;/strong&gt;. This node would act as an intermediary, handling the consensus requirements of each blockchain while allowing users to interact with cross-chain transactions with minimal latency. Such a setup could potentially reduce the time required for transaction finalization and provide a smoother user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot and Cardano Community and Ecosystem Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The success of the Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge heavily depends on the collaboration between the two communities&lt;/strong&gt;. Various stakeholders from both ecosystems, including developers, researchers, and validators, need to work together to overcome the technical challenges and build a robust bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cross-Chain Development Initiatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several cross-chain development initiatives have already begun, with developers from both Cardano and Polkadot engaging in discussions and planning sessions. These initiatives aim to gather the necessary resources, expertise, and funding to move the project forward. For example, proposals have been submitted to both &lt;strong&gt;Cardano’s Project Catalyst&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s OpenGov&lt;/strong&gt; to secure funding for the bridge’s feasibility study and subsequent phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hackathons and Collaborative Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hackathons and other collaborative events, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/web3-events/web3-summit/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3 Summit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, provide an excellent platform for developers to &lt;strong&gt;prototype and test components of the Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge&lt;/strong&gt;. These events bring together talent from across the blockchain space, fostering innovation and accelerating the bridge’s development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Challenges and Setbacks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the progress, the project has faced some setbacks, particularly in securing funding. Recent proposals submitted to Project Catalyst did not receive enough support to pass the minimum threshold for funding, &lt;strong&gt;prompting the team to revisit and improve their proposals for future funding rounds&lt;/strong&gt;. This highlights the importance of clear communication, socialization of ideas, and community engagement in the success of such ambitious projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Broader Impact of the Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful implementation of the Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge would have far-reaching implications for both ecosystems and the broader blockchain industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced DeFi and NFT Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the bridge in place, users and developers would gain access to a broader range of &lt;strong&gt;decentralized finance (DeFi)&lt;/strong&gt; applications and &lt;strong&gt;non-fungible tokens (NFTs)&lt;/strong&gt; across both networks. This could lead to the creation of new cross-chain financial products, NFT marketplaces, and other dApps that leverage the unique features of both Cardano and Polkadot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Strengthening the Web3 Ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interoperability between Cardano and Polkadot would contribute to a more cohesive Web3 ecosystem. By enabling seamless communication between two of the most advanced blockchain platforms, &lt;strong&gt;the bridge would help break down silos within the blockchain space&lt;/strong&gt;, fostering greater collaboration and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Long-Term Vision: A Connected Blockchain Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge is a step toward a future where blockchain networks are interconnected, allowing users to move assets and data freely across different platforms. This vision aligns with the broader goals of Web3, where decentralization, interoperability, and user empowerment are at the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Cardano &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Polkadot bridge&lt;/strong&gt; represents a significant milestone in the pursuit of blockchain interoperability. While the project faces considerable technical challenges, the proposed solutions and collaborative efforts from both communities offer a promising path forward. As the bridge progresses from feasibility studies to a fully functional product, it will not only benefit the Cardano and Polkadot ecosystems but also pave the way for a more interconnected and robust Web3 landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of this bridge could serve as a blueprint for future cross-chain projects, ultimately contributing to the realization of a truly decentralized and interoperable blockchain ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the disccusion at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/cardano-polkadot-bridge/8543&quot;&gt;Polkadot forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Decentralizing TikTok w/ Polkadot, Solving the US Ban</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/decentralizing-tiktok-with-polkadot-solution-to-the-us-ban/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/decentralizing-tiktok-with-polkadot-solution-to-the-us-ban/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In recent months, the United States government has been scrutinizing TikTok due to national security concerns and its connections to the Chinese government. With over 170 million users in the US alone, TikTok’s potential ban has sparked significant debate and concern among users and stakeholders alike. However, a promising solution has emerged that not only addresses these concerns but also paves the way for a new era of decentralized social networking. This solution involves the sale of TikTok to an American company that is deeply invested in Polkadot technology and the decentralization of social networks. This article delves into the potential of this solution and its implications for the future of TikTok and social media as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Urgency of TikTok’s Situation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it stands, TikTok is at a crossroads. The US government has expressed intentions to ban the app unless it is sold to an American entity. This decision is rooted in concerns over data privacy and national security, given TikTok’s ownership by the Chinese company ByteDance. In response to these concerns, US billionaire Frank McCourt has stepped forward with a bold proposition: acquire TikTok and rebuild it using decentralized technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter Frank McCourt and Project Liberty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank McCourt, former owner of the Los Angeles Dodgers, is leading a consortium to acquire TikTok. McCourt’s initiative, known as the “people’s bid,” is not just about ownership transfer but about fundamentally transforming how social networks operate. He is collaborating with investment bank Guggenheim Securities and law firm Kirkland &amp;amp; Ellis to make this vision a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of McCourt’s plan is Project Liberty, an initiative focused on decentralizing social networks to safeguard privacy and data ownership. Central to this project is the Decentralized Social Networking Protocol (DSNP), which aims to shift control from centralized entities to individual users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of Polkadot and Web3 Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot, a leading blockchain technology, offers a robust framework for building decentralized applications. Its unique architecture, consisting of multiple parachains, allows for high security and scalability. McCourt’s plan involves leveraging Polkadot’s parachain, Frequency, to rebuild TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequency, which secured its position as a parachain on the Polkadot network in November 2022, is designed to empower individuals by ensuring the portability of their content and safeguarding their privacy. This aligns perfectly with the goals of DSNP and Project Liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benefits of Decentralization for TikTok&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Privacy and Data Ownership&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the primary benefits of decentralizing TikTok is enhanced privacy and data ownership for users. Currently, social networks often treat users as products, monetizing their data without giving them control. Decentralization shifts this paradigm, giving users ownership of their digital identities and control over their data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Avenues for Content Creators&lt;/strong&gt;: Decentralized social networks offer new financial opportunities for content creators. By integrating Web3 technologies, TikTok could provide greater ownership over content and revenue streams through mechanisms like tokenization and decentralized finance (DeFi).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security and Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Polkadot’s blockchain technology offers high security and flexibility, making it an ideal platform for building decentralized social applications. This ensures that TikTok can scale efficiently while maintaining robust security measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implications for Global Adoption of Web3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential purchase and decentralization of TikTok could be a turning point in the global adoption of Web3 technologies. By demonstrating the viability of decentralized social networks on a large scale, TikTok’s transition could inspire other platforms to follow suit, accelerating the adoption of decentralized internet protocols worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Path Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the potential sale and decentralization of TikTok are still in the discussion phase, the profiles of the people involved and the technologies proposed make this a plausible and exciting prospect. Frank McCourt’s initiative has garnered support from influential figures like Gavin Wood, further bolstering its credibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this story unfolds, it will be crucial to monitor how these developments impact not only TikTok’s future but also the broader landscape of social media and internet technologies. The shift towards decentralization could mark a significant evolution in how we interact online, offering greater control and security to users globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed solution to the US ban on TikTok through its sale to an American company invested in Polkadot technology and Web3 represents a groundbreaking approach to social networking. By decentralizing TikTok, we can safeguard user privacy, provide new opportunities for content creators, and potentially drive the global adoption of Web3 technologies. This innovative approach could redefine the future of social networks, ensuring that users, not corporations, hold the power and control over their digital identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vfCnLcRlLIM?si=3NFNzSvdlibm4oEa&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded><category>business</category></item><item><title>Developer Onboarding in the Polkadot Ecosystem with Kudos</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/developer-onboarding-in-the-polkadot-ecosystem-with-kudos/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/developer-onboarding-in-the-polkadot-ecosystem-with-kudos/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudos&lt;/strong&gt; is the first-of-its-kind project aiming at smoothening the &lt;strong&gt;developer onboarding within the Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, both rich in context and fast-evolving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What stands out about Kudos is that it is built on top of the efforts like those of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://polkadot.network/development/blockchain-academy/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Blockchain Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/lists/10-key-aspects-of-the-polkadot-fellowship/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Fellowship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But the difference in this is that Kudos seems to thrive on both building a collaborative community and ongoing skill development. It is not about learning the ropes; it is about mastering them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Simplifying Onboarding Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If finding a specific place for over &lt;strong&gt;25,000 repositories t&lt;/strong&gt;o start is hard, well, consider it a needle in a haystack experience. Kudos makes that simple with a &lt;strong&gt;highly user-friendly platform that enables developers to surf, search, and filter to find the issues from GitHub effectively&lt;/strong&gt;. The mission? Get developers matched up with projects they find interesting and where they can best put their skills to work as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empowering Collaboration and Visibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.morekudos.com/&quot;&gt;Kudos&lt;/a&gt; brings visibility to your project and pulls in the perspective of your collaborator, organizing the team by interests and maturity. Intuitive navigation will guide contributors through the different teams as they work on issues. Features like &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“good first issues”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are just what it says on the tin for beginners: entry points to active projects on a fast track. You can follow&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KudosPortal&quot;&gt; Kudos on X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qfEQRX1NY0w?si=Dk_cxQka1Xvr7rzd&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Elastic Scaling for Polkadot Parachains and Cumulus Node MVP</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/elastic-scaling-polkadot-parachains-cumulus-node-mvp/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/elastic-scaling-polkadot-parachains-cumulus-node-mvp/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cumulus node has recently launched its MVP release for elastic scaling&lt;/strong&gt;, marking a pivotal moment for parachain teams. Announced on July 31, 2024, this update introduces groundbreaking features aimed at enhancing throughput and performance across the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Features of the Elastic Scaling MVP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest release, identified as stable2407 1, &lt;strong&gt;integrates support for elastic scaling into the Cumulus node&lt;/strong&gt;. This new functionality allows parachains to leverage up to three cores per relay chain block. As a result, parachains can now experience up to three times the throughput compared to previous capabilities, with block times reduced to just two seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot Relay Chain Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a relay chain perspective, the elastic scaling functionality is fully implemented and currently &lt;strong&gt;active on the Westend and Rococo testnets&lt;/strong&gt;. This feature represents a major step forward in Polkadot’s scalability efforts. However, due to security considerations, &lt;strong&gt;all nodes (collators) of an elastic parachain are required to be trusted&lt;/strong&gt;. Collators must now announce or gossip blocks only to trusted nodes, necessitating a temporary private network setup until further RFC updates are completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collator Adjustments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elastic scaling support for collators is accessible via a new, experimental slot-based collator mode. This functionality can be enabled using the node CLI switch: &lt;code&gt;--experimental-use-slot-based&lt;/code&gt;. Despite these advancements, it is important to note that the cumulus block authorship and import pipelines are not yet optimized for elastic scaling. Consequently, the maximum achievable throughput is influenced by the number of collators and their networking latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the maximum throughput achievable with elastic scaling is observed when using a single collator. In such cases, the system can achieve 1.3 seconds of execution and 5MB Proof of Validity (PoV) per parachain block, translating to a total execution time of 2.6 seconds for each relay chain block. Adding multiple collators to the set reduces the maximum execution time per block, though testing indicates that the optimal throughput with multiple collators is achievable with two cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Future Developments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot development team is committed to further optimizing the cumulus block authorship process to improve throughput limitations. The ongoing work, detailed in the GitHub issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk/issues/5190&quot;&gt;Elastic Scaling: Streamlined Block Production&lt;/a&gt;, aims to address current inefficiencies and enhance overall performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started with Elastic Scaling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For developers looking to experiment with the new elastic scaling features, the following prerequisites are necessary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polkadot binary stable2407 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polkadot-parachain binary stable2407 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latest Zombienet release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sample test for elastic scaling is available in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk/pull/0000-cumulus-3cores.zndsl&quot;&gt;Zombienet tests&lt;/a&gt;. This test spins up a Rococo development relay chain with three validators and one parachain, utilizing updated runtime support as per the documentation. Developers can run the test using the provided JavaScript script to assign cores to the parachain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those using the Polkadot parachain node template, additional instructions for incorporating elastic scaling node support can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/elastic-scaling-mvp-launched/9392&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the elastic scaling MVP is a significant milestone for the Polkadot ecosystem, offering enhanced performance and scalability for parachains. As development continues, further optimizations are expected to refine and expand these capabilities, reinforcing Polkadot’s commitment to advancing blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information you can consult the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/elastic-scaling-mvp-launched/9392&quot;&gt;original post in the Polkadot forum&lt;/a&gt; where you can continue the discussion about this news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Expected JAM Launch on July 2025?</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/expected-jam-launch-on-july-2025/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/expected-jam-launch-on-july-2025/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scytale.digital/blog-posts/attention-developers-discover-the-50-million-jam-implementers-prize-and-access-a-supercomputer-playground&quot;&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt; shared on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/scytale-digital/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scytale Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; blog, they give us an approximate date for the launch of JAM. In &lt;span style=&quot;color: #008000;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, the highly anticipated launch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/polkadot-jam-chain/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAM (Join Accumulate Machine)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is expected to usher in a new era of blockchain technology within the Polkadot ecosystem. Although it is normal to see delays in these launches, so take the date of July 2025 only as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initiative, spearheaded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/gavin-wood/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot founder Gavin Wood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has already sparked considerable interest within the blockchain community. With an impressive prize pool of 10 million DOT tokens and 100,000 KSM tokens—valued at over $60 million USD—up for grabs, developers worldwide are gearing up to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/shape-polkadots-future-with-the-jam-prize-10m-dot/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAM Prize competition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, aiming to create robust client implementations that enhance Polkadot’s network resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of JAM represents a significant leap in Polkadot’s ongoing evolution, pushing the boundaries of what blockchain technology can achieve. For years, Polkadot has been at the forefront of decentralization, interoperability, and scalability. However, JAM is poised to take these capabilities to the next level by offering a &lt;strong&gt;more flexible and efficient infrastructure layer&lt;/strong&gt;, moving away from the rigid limitations of parachains and fostering a more seamless integration for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Vision Behind JAM: A Decentralized Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot has always aimed to build a truly decentralized and resilient blockchain network, but the path to achieving that vision has not been without challenges. The introduction of JAM is a direct response to some of the hurdles faced by developers and users within the current blockchain ecosystem. One of the main issues Polkadot has identified is the need for a more flexible platform that allows developers to build solutions without the necessity of creating or maintaining their own blockchains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, most integrations within the Polkadot ecosystem have relied heavily on parachains, &lt;strong&gt;parallel blockchains that run alongside Polkadot and are connected through the Relay chain&lt;/strong&gt;. While this architecture provides a high level of security and scalability, it has also created&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;fragmentation and alignment issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, especially for early-stage projects. Many developers have found it difficult to leverage existing parachains effectively, often dedicating significant resources to building chains even when their applications didn’t require a full blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JAM is Polkadot’s answer to these limitations, offering a more flexible and scalable infrastructure that allows for broader use cases and easier integration. &lt;strong&gt;With JAM, developers are no longer restricted to parachains&lt;/strong&gt; but can work within a more decentralized and less opinionated infrastructure layer, creating an ecosystem that is far more adaptable to diverse needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;JAM’s Core Features: A Deep Dive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
At the heart of the JAM initiative lies a robust protocol designed to optimize the performance, security, and adaptability of the Polkadot network. While the JAM protocol is backward compatible with existing Polkadot architecture, it introduces several new features that promise to revolutionize how developers build and scale decentralized applications (dApps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Backwards Compatibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JAM has been engineered to ensure that developers and users can &lt;strong&gt;transition seamlessly from Polkadot’s current Relay chain architecture to the new JAM protocol&lt;/strong&gt;. Backward compatibility means that all existing parachains, smart contracts, and applications will continue to function as intended, without requiring major rewrites or migrations. This is critical for maintaining the continuity and stability of the Polkadot ecosystem as it evolves toward JAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Redundancy of the Relay Chain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more radical changes introduced by JAM is the redundancy of the Relay chain. With the deployment of JAM, the Relay chain, which has historically played a central role in securing the Polkadot network, will no longer be necessary. &lt;strong&gt;Validators who previously secured the Relay chain can migrate to the new JAM-based architecture&lt;/strong&gt;. While it’s possible to continue running the Relay chain via hard forks, validators will no longer receive rewards unless they transition to the new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shift underscores Polkadot’s vision of decentralizing the core functions of its network, distributing security and economic functions across a more flexible and resilient infrastructure. By eliminating the dependency on a central security chain, JAM aims to enhance the scalability and efficiency of the entire Polkadot ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optimized Resource Allocation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JAM’s protocol upgrades also aim to streamline resource allocation across the Polkadot network. &lt;strong&gt;By decentralizing extraneous functionalities that were previously tied to the Relay chain&lt;/strong&gt;, JAM allows for more efficient use of computational resources. This optimization is particularly important for large-scale enterprise solutions and dApps that require high levels of performance and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhanced Security and Resilience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security has always been a top priority for Polkadot, and JAM continues this tradition by incentivizing the development of multiple client implementations. &lt;strong&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/shape-polkadots-future-with-the-jam-prize-10m-dot/&quot;&gt;JAM Prize&lt;/a&gt; encourages developers to create implementations in various programming languages&lt;/strong&gt;, ensuring that the network is not overly reliant on any single client or programming language. This diversity of implementations significantly enhances network resilience, &lt;strong&gt;reducing the risk of vulnerabilities that could arise from monoculture in software&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The JAM Supercomputer: Testing the Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting aspects of the JAM initiative is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/the-jam-toaster-testing-at-scale-for-the-future-of-blockchain/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAM Supercomputer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the JAM Toaster. Unveiled in Lisbon earlier this year, this state-of-the-art system is designed to run the Polkadot Virtual Machine (PVM) and serve as a centralized testing hub for the JAM network. With 12,276 cores and 16 TB of RAM, the JAM Toaster is a computational powerhouse capable of simulating the entire JAM network’s functionality before full deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JAM Supercomputer is not just a testing environment; it’s a critical tool for developers aiming to optimize their JAM implementations. By leveraging the Toaster’s vast computational resources, developers can conduct extensive testing, experimentation, and optimization to ensure that their solutions are scalable and secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Global Node Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the JAM Toaster, Polkadot plans to deploy a distributed network of 1,023 nodes worldwide. These nodes collectively replicate the behavior of the JAM network, allowing for more comprehensive testing across different geographical locations and network conditions. This distributed network will &lt;strong&gt;simulate the processing power of 341 cores&lt;/strong&gt;, providing developers with a highly accurate and scalable testing environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Top-Tier Computing Power&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/the-jam-toaster-testing-at-scale-for-the-future-of-blockchain/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JAM Supercomputer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and its distributed nodes are expected to rank among the top 500–1000 supercomputers globally, a testament to the technological significance and computational power of the JAM initiative. By leveraging this advanced infrastructure, Polkadot is setting the stage for a new era of decentralized network validation and scalability.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mEhj1_KQ1rU?si=-AOpftvFaX0sxm2S&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The JAM Prize: Empowering Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the JAM initiative is the JAM Prize, a massive incentive program designed to encourage developers to contribute to Polkadot’s future. &lt;strong&gt;With a prize pool valued at over $60 million USD&lt;/strong&gt;, the JAM Prize offers significant financial rewards for developers who successfully complete key milestones in implementing JAM client software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prize Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JAM Prize pool consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 million DOT tokens&lt;/strong&gt; (valued at over $60 million USD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100,000 KSM tokens&lt;/strong&gt; (valued at approximately $1.8 million USD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These funds will be awarded to developers who meet specific milestones, with &lt;strong&gt;grants of up to 500,000 DOT and 5,000 KSM per completed implementation&lt;/strong&gt;. The prize incentivizes development in multiple programming languages, divided into four categories: “Cooperate Code” (AspectJ, Kotlin, C#, Go), “Quick Code” (C, C++, Rust, etc.), “Cute Code” (Python, Ruby, Haskell, etc.), and “Correct Code” (Ada, Julia, Erlang, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Milestones for Success&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To win prizes, developers must complete five key milestones, which include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importer&lt;/strong&gt;: State-transitioning conformance tests must pass, and the system should be capable of importing blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: The implementation must be fully conformant and capable of producing blocks, including networking and off-chain functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half-speed&lt;/strong&gt;: The system must demonstrate Kusama-level performance, including the implementation of the PVM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full-speed&lt;/strong&gt;: The implementation must achieve Polkadot-level performance, passing all necessary performance tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure&lt;/strong&gt;: The system must pass a comprehensive security audit, ensuring robustness against potential vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion: The Road Ahead for JAM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Polkadot embarks on the next phase of its journey with the launch of JAM, the blockchain industry is poised for a major shift. JAM represents a significant upgrade to Polkadot’s architecture, offering a more flexible, scalable, and resilient platform for developers and users alike. By decentralizing key network functions and incentivizing the development of diverse client implementations, Polkadot is positioning itself as a leader in the next generation of blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For developers, &lt;strong&gt;the JAM Prize offers an unparalleled opportunity to contribute to Polkadot’s future&lt;/strong&gt;, with the potential to earn substantial rewards while helping to shape the future of web3. As the blockchain ecosystem continues to evolve, JAM stands as a beacon of innovation, security, and resilience—a testament to Polkadot’s commitment to building a truly decentralized future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the article by &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/mark_cachia_&quot;&gt;Mark Cachia&lt;/a&gt; posted on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/scytale-digital/&quot;&gt;Scytale Digita&lt;/a&gt;l&lt;/strong&gt; website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scytale.digital/blog-posts/attention-developers-discover-the-50-million-jam-implementers-prize-and-access-a-supercomputer-playground&quot;&gt;JAM Launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Exploring Reactive DOT Tool for Polkadot Development</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/exploring-reactive-dot-tool-for-polkadot-development/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/exploring-reactive-dot-tool-for-polkadot-development/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Reactive DOT is one such tool that has been gaining traction within the Polkadot ecosystem. Supported by the successful &lt;strong&gt;proposals #812 and #948&lt;/strong&gt; and created by Tiến Nguyễn Khắc, Reactive DOT introduces &lt;strong&gt;a new approach to handling state management and front-end interfaces in Polkadot-based applications&lt;/strong&gt;. This article provides an in-depth look at Reactive DOT, its features, and how it can be leveraged by developers to enhance their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Reactive DOT?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive DOT is a &lt;strong&gt;framework designed to streamline the development process for dApps on the Polkadot network&lt;/strong&gt;. By focusing on reactive programming principles, Reactive DOT offers a more &lt;strong&gt;efficient way to manage state and build user interfaces that are both dynamic and responsive&lt;/strong&gt;. This tool is particularly valuable for developers looking to create applications that require real-time updates and seamless interactions with the Polkadot network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Features of Reactive DOT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive DOT comes packed with features that make it an invaluable resource for developers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asynchronous State Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Reactive DOT allows developers to handle state changes asynchronously, ensuring that applications remain responsive even during high transaction volumes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time Data Handling&lt;/strong&gt;: The framework is built to manage real-time data streams, making it ideal for applications that require instant updates and live data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified Front-End Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: With its focus on front-end interfaces, Reactive DOT simplifies the process of building user interfaces that are both intuitive and efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compatibility with Polkadot&lt;/strong&gt;: Reactive DOT is fully integrated with the Polkadot network, providing developers with the tools they need to build advanced dApps that leverage Polkadot’s capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of PAPI (Polkadot API) in Reactive DOT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the core of Reactive DOT’s functionality is &lt;a href=&quot;https://papi.how/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAPI (Polkadot API)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which serves as the engine driving the interaction with the Polkadot network. &lt;strong&gt;PAPI provides the necessary APIs to facilitate a wide range of operations&lt;/strong&gt;, from basic node interactions to complex governance and staking functions. By integrating PAPI with Reactive DOT, developers can create applications that are not only powerful but also future-ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real-World Application: The DOT Console&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To showcase the capabilities of Reactive DOT, a developer console application, known as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dot-console.pages.dev/&quot;&gt;DOT Console&lt;/a&gt;, was developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/TienNguyenK&quot;&gt;Tiến Nguyễn Khắc&lt;/a&gt;, the creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactivedot.dev/&quot;&gt;Reactive DOT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This console serves as a practical demonstration of how Reactive DOT can be used in real-world scenarios to create efficient and scalable dApps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features of the DOT Console&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DOT Console application highlights several key features of Reactive DOT, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalistic Statistics &amp;amp; Blocks Viewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides users with a simple yet effective interface for viewing blockchain statistics and blocks in real-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallet Connection Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows users to connect their wallets seamlessly, leveraging the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dotconnect.dev/getting-started.html&quot;&gt;DOT Connect UI library&lt;/a&gt; for managing wallet interactions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage, Constants &amp;amp; Runtime APIs Querying&lt;/strong&gt;: Enables developers to query various blockchain elements, such as storage, constants, and runtime APIs, directly from the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extrinsic Builder&lt;/strong&gt;: Offers a tool for constructing extrinsics, ranging from simple remarks to complex cross-chain messages (XCM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Value of Dogfooding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the development of the&lt;a href=&quot;https://dot-console.pages.dev/&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;DOT Console&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the concept of “dogfooding” was employed—using one’s own product to validate its effectiveness. By building a real-world application with Reactive DOT and PAPI, the developer was able to test the performance, efficacy, and developer ergonomics of these tools in a practical setting. This approach not only demonstrated the capabilities of Reactive DOT but also provided valuable insights into how it can be further refined and optimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Future of Polkadot Development with Reactive DOT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactive DOT represents an advancement in the tools available to Polkadot developers. By offering a framework that prioritizes real-time data handling, asynchronous state management, and seamless front-end integration, Reactive DOT positions itself as a go-to resource for building next-generation dApps on the Polkadot network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As developers begin to explore and implement Reactive DOT in their projects, the feedback and experiences they share will be crucial in shaping the future of this tool. Whether you’re a seasoned Polkadot developer or just starting, &lt;strong&gt;Reactive DOT&lt;/strong&gt;, combined with PAPI, offers the potential to revolutionize how you approach dApp development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those not yet ready to dive into Reactive DOT, it’s still highly recommended to utilize &lt;strong&gt;PAPI&lt;/strong&gt; for all future Polkadot projects. &lt;strong&gt;Migrating from older frameworks like PJS to PAPI&lt;/strong&gt; can provide significant performance improvements and future-proof your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Reactive DOT, supported by PAPI, is set to play a pivotal role in the evolution of Polkadot development, offering developers the tools they need to create more efficient, scalable, and responsive applications within this rapidly growing ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the discussion at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/show-and-tell-reactivedot-x-papi/9388&quot;&gt;Polkadot Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Improving Polkadot Developer Experience</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/improving-polkadot-developer-experience/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/improving-polkadot-developer-experience/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As the Polkadot ecosystem grows, so does the demand for a seamless and enriching developer experience. In an effort to gather &lt;strong&gt;insights and identify any gaps within this experience&lt;/strong&gt;, the Polkadot community has initiated a &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/CyG4JGahyWwks46K8&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aimed at understanding what is missing for developers working within the ecosystem, shared in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/polkadot-developer-experience-whats-missing-survey/9520&quot;&gt;polkadot forum topic&lt;/a&gt; created by &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/baderyo_o&quot;&gt;Bader&lt;/a&gt;. This article delves into the survey’s findings, exploring the sentiments, thoughts, and suggestions from developers and stakeholders to enhance the overall Polkadot developer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding the Developer Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;developer experience (DX)&lt;/strong&gt; is a crucial component of any technological ecosystem. It encompasses everything from onboarding new developers to the ease of use and comprehensiveness of documentation, the availability of tools and resources, and the overall satisfaction of developers as they build and deploy applications. For Polkadot, a multifaceted protocol that includes core infrastructure, smart contracts, and a wide array of decentralized applications (dApps), the &lt;strong&gt;DX is particularly complex and demands careful attention&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Importance of Developer Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the primary areas of concern highlighted in the survey is the &lt;strong&gt;quality and availability of developer documentation&lt;/strong&gt;. Documentation is the cornerstone of the developer experience, providing the necessary guidance and knowledge for developers to build efficiently and effectively. Unfortunately, this is an area where Polkadot has been identified as having significant room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot SDK i&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s recognized as a powerful tool, the documentation surrounding it often falls short. Developers have expressed frustrations with the lack of clear, comprehensive, and up-to-date documentation. This gap not only hinders the onboarding of new developers but also slows down the productivity of experienced ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “&lt;em&gt;documentation&lt;/em&gt;” itself is broad and can encompass various components, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction and Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing a clear explanation of the Polkadot ecosystem, its architecture, and its potential use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation Guides:&lt;/strong&gt; Step-by-step instructions for setting up the development environment and dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beginner’s Guides:&lt;/strong&gt; Quickstart guides that help new developers get up and running with minimal friction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conceptual Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; Detailed explanations of key concepts, terminology, and design decisions within Polkadot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tutorials:&lt;/strong&gt; Practical, goal-oriented guides that walk developers through the process of building specific applications or features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Topics:&lt;/strong&gt; In-depth resources for experienced developers, covering complex subjects like bridge integration and parachain development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey revealed that while some of these components are present, they are often fragmented, outdated, or incomplete. This has led to a disjointed developer experience, where finding the right information can be time-consuming and frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Need for Use-Case Driven Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another recurring theme in the survey is the demand for more use-case-driven documentation. Developers are not just looking for theoretical knowledge; they want to see real-world examples of how Polkadot can be used to solve practical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach would involve creating documentation that focuses on specific use cases, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building a Decentralized Marketplace:&lt;/strong&gt; A step-by-step guide to creating a trustless marketplace on Polkadot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing Supply Chain Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt; Showcasing how Polkadot’s decentralized infrastructure can be used to improve transparency and efficiency in supply chain management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing Social Media Platforms:&lt;/strong&gt; Exploring how Polkadot can power next-generation social media applications with enhanced privacy and security features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By providing these examples, developers can better understand the potential of Polkadot and how it can be applied to various industry verticals. This not only enhances the developer experience but also drives innovation within the ecosystem by encouraging developers to think beyond the traditional DeFi applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of the Polkadot SDK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot SDK is a powerful and flexible tool that enables developers to build a wide range of applications within the Polkadot ecosystem. However, as the survey indicates, there is still much to be done to improve its accessibility and usability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges highlighted is the lack of comprehensive guides that cover the full-stack development process. Developers want to know how to build complete applications, from front-end to back-end, using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paritytech/polkadot-sdk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot SDK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This requires detailed documentation that not only explains the technical aspects of the SDK but also provides guidance on how to integrate it with other tools and technologies commonly used in Web3 development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the survey suggests that the Polkadot SDK could benefit from better tooling and support. This include&lt;strong&gt;s improving the developer tools available within the Polkadot SDK&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as providing more robust support channels for developers who encounter issues. The goal should be to create an environment where developers can focus on building innovative applications without being bogged down by technical hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Importance of Developer Support and Community Engagement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer support is another critical aspect of the DX that was highlighted in the survey. While Polkadot has a vibrant and active community, there are still gaps in the support available to developers, &lt;strong&gt;particularly those who are new to the ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey respondents expressed a need for more accessible and responsive support channels. This includes not only traditional support methods, such as forums and help desks, but also more interactive and real-time options, such as chat support and live coding sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to support, the survey underscored the importance of community engagement. Developers want to feel connected to the Polkadot ecosystem and to other developers working within it. This can be achieved through &lt;strong&gt;regular community events, hackathons, and meetups&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as through the &lt;strong&gt;creation of more collaborative spaces&lt;/strong&gt; where developers can share ideas, ask questions, and work together on projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bridging the Gap Between Web2 and Web3 Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the broader challenges identified in the survey is the gap between traditional Web2 development and the new paradigms introduced by Web3 technologies like Polkadot. For many developers, transitioning from Web2 to Web3 can be a daunting process, requiring them to &lt;strong&gt;learn new concepts, tools, and workflows&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey suggests that more effort needs to be put into easing this transition. This could involve &lt;strong&gt;creating documentation and resources specifically tailored to Web2 developers&lt;/strong&gt;, helping them understand the key differences and similarities between the two worlds. It could also involve providing more examples of how traditional Web2 applications can be reimagined and improved using Web3 technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, a guide on how to build a Web3 version of a popular Web2 application, such as an e-commerce platform or social media site, could be incredibly valuable. This would not only help Web2 developers get started with Polkadot but also demonstrate the unique advantages that Web3 can offer, such as enhanced security, decentralization, and user ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion: The Path Forward for Polkadot Developer Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot developer experience is at a crucial juncture. While the ecosystem offers powerful tools and infrastructure, there are still significant gaps that need to be addressed to ensure a seamless and productive experience for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey has provided valuable insights into what developers are looking for, &lt;strong&gt;highlighting the need for better documentation, more use-case-driven resources, improved developer support&lt;/strong&gt;, and a stronger focus on bridging the gap between Web2 and Web3 development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Polkadot community continues to grow and evolve, it is essential to prioritize these areas and work towards creating an environment where developers can thrive. By doing so, Polkadot can not only attract more developers to its ecosystem but also empower them to build the next generation of decentralized applications that will drive the Web3 revolution forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the success of Polkadot depends on its ability to provide a developer experience that is not only functional but also inspiring. By listening to the feedback from the survey and taking meaningful action, Polkadot can ensure that it remains at the forefront of blockchain innovation and continues to be a leading platform for developers in the Web3 space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/polkadot-developer-experience-whats-missing-survey/9520&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow the discussion at the Polkadot Forum.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Improving Transparency in Polkadot OpenGov Bounties</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/improving-transparency-polkadot-opengov-bounties/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/improving-transparency-polkadot-opengov-bounties/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s OpenGov system&lt;/strong&gt; represents a revolutionary approach to decentralized governance, enabling community-driven decisions that shape the future of the ecosystem. One of the critical components of this system is the &lt;strong&gt;bounty program&lt;/strong&gt;, which incentivizes contributors to work on various initiatives that benefit the broader community. However, as the ecosystem grows, so does the complexity of tracking these bounties, particularly the child bounties that are part of larger initiatives. This article delves into the current state of &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot OpenGov bounty tracking&lt;/strong&gt;, highlighting the challenges and proposing solutions to improve transparency and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/necessary-improvements-in-transparency-and-bounty-tracking-in-opengov/9419&quot;&gt;Polkadot forum Lily Mendez opened a discussion on this topic&lt;/a&gt; (you can follow &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/lily_mendz&quot;&gt;Lily Mendez on X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-11216&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_11216&quot; style=&quot;width: 743px&quot;&gt;![polkadot bounties list](../../uploads/2024/08/polkadot-bounties-list.webp)&lt;figcaption class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot; id=&quot;caption-attachment-11216&quot;&gt;[polkadot bounties list](https://volcano-chopper-8c4.notion.site/Bounties-Child-Bounties-Polkadot-0bcf65ab6ff941c08c96514be9cb511a) by Lily Mendez.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Polkadot OpenGov Bounties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What Are OpenGov Bounties?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;bounties are funding mechanisms that allow the community to propose and execute projects that contribute to the network’s growth&lt;/strong&gt;. These bounties can cover a wide range of activities, from development and security to marketing and community engagement. &lt;strong&gt;The bounty process is designed to be transparent and inclusive&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing anyone in the community to propose a bounty, which is then voted on by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Role of Child Bounties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Child bounties are a subset of larger parent bounties, created to tackle specific tasks within a broader project. For instance, a parent bounty might focus on improving the overall security of the Polkadot network, while child bounties under it could address particular vulnerabilities or create &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/web3-learn/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;educational resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about security best practices. While child bounties are an effective way to break down complex projects into manageable tasks, tracking them has proven to be a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Importance of Transparency in Bounty Tracking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Transparency Matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency in bounty tracking is crucial for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Trust&lt;/strong&gt;: Transparency fosters trust within the community, &lt;strong&gt;ensuring that funds are allocated appropriately&lt;/strong&gt; and that projects are progressing as intended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;: When community members can easily track bounties, they are more likely to participate, either by contributing directly to the projects or by proposing new ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability&lt;/strong&gt;: Clear tracking ensures that curators and implementers are held accountable for their work, reducing the risk of mismanagement or fraud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current Challenges in Bounty Tracking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the importance of transparency, several challenges currently hinder effective &lt;strong&gt;bounty tracking in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of Centralized Information&lt;/strong&gt;: There is no single platform where users can view all active and completed bounties, particularly child bounties. Information is often scattered across different platforms, making it difficult for users to get a comprehensive overview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inconsistent Data Availability&lt;/strong&gt;: Not all bounties provide detailed information about their progress, curators, or outcomes. This lack of consistency makes it hard for users to assess the effectiveness of the bounty system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Access to Curator Information&lt;/strong&gt;: In many cases, the curators responsible for managing bounties are not easily accessible, and their social media or contact information is not provided. This lack of transparency can lead to &lt;strong&gt;questions about the accountability of those managing significant funds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proposed Solutions for Improving Bounty Tracking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Developing a Centralized Bounty Tracking Platform&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most effective ways to address the challenges of bounty tracking is by developing a centralized platform where all bounties, including child bounties, can be tracked in real time. Such a platform could include the following features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;: A single dashboard that displays all active, completed, and canceled bounties, with filters to sort by category, status, or proposer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detailed Bounty Information&lt;/strong&gt;: Each bounty entry should include comprehensive details such as the parent bounty number, title, short description, proposer, status, approved referendum, curators, and type (e.g., marketing, development).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curator Profiles&lt;/strong&gt;: Profiles for curators that include their social media links, previous bounties managed, and a reputation score based on community feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Enhancing Data Availability and Consistency&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve data consistency across bounties, the following steps could be implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standardized Bounty Templates&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduce a standardized template for all bounty proposals, ensuring that essential information is provided in a consistent format. This template could include fields for &lt;strong&gt;project milestones, deliverables, and timelines&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Require curators and implementers to provide regular updates on the progress of their bounties, including any challenges faced and how they are being addressed. These updates should be &lt;strong&gt;publicly accessible on the centralized platform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration with Existing Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Leverage existing tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/polkassembly/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkassembly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/subsquare/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subsquare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to provide automatic updates on bounty statuses, reducing the manual effort required to keep the community informed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improving Curator Accountability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enhance accountability among curators, the following measures could be considered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparent Selection Process&lt;/strong&gt;: Implement a transparent selection process for curators, where community members can vote on who should manage a particular bounty based on their experience and track record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance-Based Rewards&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduce a performance-based reward system where curators are incentivized to deliver high-quality results. Curators who consistently meet or exceed expectations could receive additional rewards, while those who fail to deliver could face penalties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Feedback Mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;: Create a feedback mechanism where community members can rate curators and provide feedback on their performance. This feedback should be visible to the entire community, helping to build or diminish a curator’s reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Case Studies: Successful Bounty Tracking Initiatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Anti-Scam Bounty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/polkadot-anti-scam-team/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Anti-Scam Bounty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a prime example of a well-structured bounty that benefits from clear tracking and community involvement. The bounty aims to &lt;strong&gt;fight scams and protect users within the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It is an open-ended bounty, with funds distributed through child bounties that address various aspects of the anti-scam response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features that contribute to its success include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparent Goals&lt;/strong&gt;: The bounty has clear, well-defined goals that are communicated to the community from the outset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: The curators provide regular updates on the progress of the bounty, ensuring that the community is kept informed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Involvement&lt;/strong&gt;: The bounty encourages community members to get involved by proposing new child bounties or contributing to existing ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Events Reward Bounty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Community Events Reward Bounty&lt;/strong&gt; is another example of effective bounty tracking. This bounty was created to &lt;strong&gt;reward community event activities in the Polkadot and Kusama ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt; through child bounties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sets this bounty apart is its focus on quick turnaround times and clear communication with the community. By providing regular updates and ensuring that all child bounties are tracked on a centralized platform, the curators have built trust and encouraged widespread participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Future of Bounty Tracking in the Polkadot Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Polkadot ecosystem continues to grow, &lt;strong&gt;the importance of effective bounty tracking will only increase&lt;/strong&gt;. By implementing the solutions proposed in this article, the community can improve transparency, foster greater engagement, and ensure that the bounty system remains a vital tool for driving innovation and growth within the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, it will be essential for the Polkadot community to remain vigilant and continue to &lt;strong&gt;refine the bounty tracking process&lt;/strong&gt;. By doing so, the ecosystem can maintain its reputation as a leader in decentralized governance and continue to attract top talent and innovative projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot’s OpenGov bounty system is a powerful tool for driving community-led innovation and growth. However, to realize its full potential, &lt;strong&gt;the system must be transparent, accessible, and accountable&lt;/strong&gt;. By addressing the current challenges in bounty tracking and implementing the proposed solutions, the Polkadot community can ensure that the bounty system remains effective and continues to benefit the ecosystem as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of Polkadot depends on the community’s ability to adapt and improve its governance processes. By enhancing bounty tracking, the ecosystem can maintain its position at the forefront of decentralized technology and continue to lead the way in building a more open, transparent, and inclusive digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the discussión at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/necessary-improvements-in-transparency-and-bounty-tracking-in-opengov/9419&quot;&gt;Polkadot Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content:encoded><category>governance</category></item><item><title>Integration of Move VM with Substrate</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/integration-of-move-vm-with-substrate/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/integration-of-move-vm-with-substrate/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In an impressive leap forward for blockchain technology, &lt;strong&gt;the integration of the Move Virtual Machine (Move VM) with Substrate-based blockchains has been successfully accomplished by Eiger Co&lt;/strong&gt;. This landmark achievement paves the way for a new level of interoperability and functionality within the Polkadot ecosystem, enabling developers to leverage the robust capabilities of the Move programming language while building on Substrate networks. This article delves into the significance of this integration, the technical intricacies involved, and the broader implications for the blockchain community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background of Move and Substrate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move is a highly secure and verified programming language, originally developed by Diem (formerly known as Facebook’s Libra) and has gained traction with blockchains like Sui and Aptos. It was designed as a platform-agnostic language, emphasizing security and formal verification to ensure robust smart contract execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substrate, on the other hand, is a modular framework that enables the creation of purpose-built blockchains. As the underlying framework for Polkadot, Substrate provides developers with the tools to create custom blockchains with interoperability at their core. The integration of Move VM into Substrate signifies a convergence of these two powerful technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Achieving Compatibility: The Technical Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of integrating Move VM with Substrate involved several technical milestones. The team at Eiger Co. adapted the existing Diem-based Move VM to achieve full compatibility within the Substrate runtime. This adaptation was not merely a straightforward port but required substantial modification and optimization to ensure seamless operation within the Substrate environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MoveVM Adaptation:&lt;/strong&gt; The original Move VM was forked and adapted to be fully compatible with Substrate. Key steps included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backend Interface:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing a simplified Move VM backend interface with full no-std support, encapsulating all Move VM handling operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage and Address Mapping:&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing a direct mapping between the 32-byte address space in Move VM storage and Substrate accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move Smart Contract Compiler:&lt;/strong&gt; Setting up a dedicated compiler and package tool capable of supporting SS58 accounts, essential for preparing Move smart contracts for execution within the Substrate runtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pallet Move Design:&lt;/strong&gt; The Move pallet is central to this integration, allowing the publishing and execution of Move modules and scripts. Three critical extrinsic calls were defined:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;execute(origin, transaction_bc, gas_limit, cheque_limit):&lt;/strong&gt; Facilitates the execution of Move scripts, supporting multiple signers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;publish_module(origin, bytecode, gas_limit):&lt;/strong&gt; Enables the publishing of individual Move modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;publish_module_bundle(origin, bundle, gas_limit):&lt;/strong&gt; Allows the publishing of bundled Move modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These calls are designed to integrate seamlessly with the Substrate runtime, translating signed origins into authorized Move account access and managing the execution parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gas Costs and Benchmarking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant aspect of the integration was establishing a balanced gas cost system. The Move VM calculates gas costs for each instruction, which are then converted to Substrate weights, translating into blockchain fees. This linear relationship between Move VM gas and Substrate weights ensures transparent and predictable cost management for developers and users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiger Co. conducted extensive benchmarking to fine-tune this relationship. By using parameterized Substrate benchmark functions and Move example code, they achieved an almost perfectly linear correlation between gas costs and Substrate weights. This precision allows for accurate gas estimation and cost management, further enhancing the usability of Move on Substrate-based networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implications for the Blockchain Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration of Move VM with Substrate unlocks a plethora of opportunities for developers and the broader blockchain ecosystem. Key benefits include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Interoperability:&lt;/strong&gt; Developers can now create Move-based smart contracts that operate seamlessly within the Polkadot ecosystem, facilitating cross-chain interactions and broadening the scope of decentralized applications (dApps).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security and Verification:&lt;/strong&gt; Move’s emphasis on security and formal verification aligns with the high standards of the Substrate framework, ensuring robust and reliable smart contract execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer Flexibility:&lt;/strong&gt; The ability to leverage Move’s capabilities within Substrate provides developers with greater flexibility in choosing the best tools for their specific needs, fostering innovation and diversity in blockchain solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move VM Substrate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substrate blockchains can now execute Move smart contracts, and Move parachains can be built on Polkadot, thanks to the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eiger_co?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@eiger_co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This integration will open new avenues for developers to leverage Move’s capabilities while building on…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Polkadot (@Polkadot) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Polkadot/status/1816109501394637034?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 24, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiger Co.’s successful integration of Move VM with Substrate marks a significant milestone for the Polkadot ecosystem and the blockchain community at large. By bridging these two powerful technologies, developers are empowered to create more secure, interoperable, and innovative applications. Comprehensive documentation and tutorials provided by Eiger Co. ensure that developers can quickly adopt and maximize the potential of this integration. As the blockchain landscape continues to evolve, such advancements are crucial in driving forward the capabilities and adoption of decentralized technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more detailed information and to stay updated on future developments, visit the project repositories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eigerco/pallet-move&quot;&gt;Pallet Move&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eigerco/substrate-stdlib&quot;&gt;Substrate Stdlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eigerco/substrate-move&quot;&gt;Substrate Move&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eigerco/move-stdlib&quot;&gt;Move Stdlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Eiger Co. encourages the community to reach out them with any questions or feedback. This integration is not just a technical achievement but a testament to the collaborative spirit and innovative drive that defines the blockchain industry. More &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiger.co/blog/eiger-brings-move-to-polkadot&quot;&gt;info about the Pallet Move in the Eiger Co. website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Introducing Polkadot Plaza: The Future of Polkadot</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/introducing-polkadot-plaza-a-vision-for-the-future-of-polkadot/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/introducing-polkadot-plaza-a-vision-for-the-future-of-polkadot/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Polkadot has continuously pushed the boundaries of scalability and functionality. A recent proposal by &lt;strong&gt;Robert Habermeier&lt;/strong&gt;, a key figure in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, introduces a transformative vision for a new system chain, codenamed &lt;em&gt;“Polkadot Plaza.”&lt;/em&gt; This concept aims to consolidate various functionalities into a single, highly scalable chain that could serve as a central hub for users, developers, liquidity, and applications within the Polkadot ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Vision Behind Polkadot Plaza&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkadot Plaza&lt;/em&gt; is designed to be an evolution of the existing &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot AssetHub chain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Currently, the ecosystem splits functionalities—such as asset issuance, smart contracts, staking, and bridging—across different chains. This fragmentation has led to increased complexity for users and developers alike. Habermeier’s proposal suggests that by consolidating these features into a single system chain, Polkadot can create a &lt;strong&gt;more user-friendly and developer-centric environment&lt;/strong&gt;, maximizing the use of the network’s resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Features of Polkadot Plaza&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habermeier outlines several core functionalities that Polkadot Plaza would integrate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Issuance:&lt;/strong&gt; Building on the existing capabilities of AssetHub, Plaza would continue to support asset issuance, maintaining the momentum of current integrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts (via RISC-V/PolkaVM):&lt;/strong&gt; The proposal includes support for both Rust-based smart contracts (via Ink!) and EVM-compatible contracts, enabling developers to use familiar tools within the Polkadot ecosystem. This would significantly lower the barriers to entry for deploying smart contracts on Polkadot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staking:&lt;/strong&gt; While staking currently occurs on the Relay Chain, Polkadot Plaza would introduce native staking capabilities, enhancing security and decentralization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bridging Pallets:&lt;/strong&gt; Plaza would integrate bridging pallets, currently managed by BridgeHub, facilitating seamless interoperability between Polkadot and other blockchain networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Near-Zero Fees:&lt;/strong&gt; To remain competitive, Polkadot Plaza aims to minimize transaction fees, especially during the initial phases, until scaling limits are reached.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot Plaza Addressing Fragmentation and Complexity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the primary challenges in the current Polkadot ecosystem is the complexity associated with interacting across multiple chains. Users must manage assets, accounts, and states across different platforms, while developers face significant overhead in building, maintaining, and integrating chains. Polkadot Plaza seeks to simplify these processes by offering a unified platform where most interactions can occur, reducing the need for coordination across disparate chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach contrasts with the current trend of asynchronous composability, where functionalities are spread across various chains. While this model may be necessary once scaling limits are reached, Habermeier argues that a more strategic focus on usability is required in the interim. By concentrating resources on a synchronous, composable system chain, &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot can better serve its growing user base and developer community&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Leveraging Elastic Scaling for Massive Throughput&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of Elastic Scaling, Polkadot will soon be able to process a large number of transactions in parallel across multiple cores. Polkadot Plaza is poised to take full advantage of this capability, &lt;strong&gt;potentially scaling to thousands of transactions per second (TPS)&lt;/strong&gt; in the short term and much higher volumes over time. This scalability would allow Polkadot to accommodate tens of millions of daily users, making it a formidable competitor to other blockchain platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Value Accrual and the Future of DOT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another significant aspect of the Polkadot Plaza proposal is the potential for value accrual to the DOT token. Habermeier suggests implementing a priority fee mechanism, where users can pay for transaction ordering priority. This approach could capture value even in a system where the average transaction fee is near zero. The revenue generated from these priority fees could be used to burn DOT tokens, potentially increasing their value over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/edjAVa5CDsQ?si=oUI3vecZE665Orrh&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Path Forward for Polkadot Plaza&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habermeier’s proposal is the first step towards formalizing Polkadot Plaza as a central component of the Polkadot ecosystem. The next steps will involve several referendums within Polkadot’s governance framework to approve and implement the necessary changes. These include renaming AssetHub to reflect its broader purpose, scaling Plaza using Polkadot cores, and integrating additional features like smart contracts and priority fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the proposal envisions making Polkadot Plaza a focal point for marketing, developer relations, and educational programs within the ecosystem. By doing so, Polkadot can create a thriving environment that attracts new users and developers, fostering innovation and growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot Plaza represents a bold and strategic vision for the future of the Polkadot ecosystem. By consolidating key functionalities into a single, scalable system chain, Polkadot can streamline user and developer experiences, enhance security and decentralization, and position itself as a leader in the blockchain space. As the community discusses and refines this proposal, &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Plaza could become the central hub from which the entire ecosystem grows and evolves&lt;/strong&gt;, laying the groundwork for the next era of blockchain innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Polkadot Mobile App for Blockchain Mass Adoption</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/introducing-the-polkadot-mobile-app-for-blockchain-mass-adoption/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/introducing-the-polkadot-mobile-app-for-blockchain-mass-adoption/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;One of the most pressing challenges of Polkadot technology is making it accessible and user-friendly for the general public. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;has taken a significant step forward in addressing this challenge with the introduction of its new mobile app. This app is designed to &lt;strong&gt;provide a seamless and intuitive experience&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing the benefits of blockchain to everyday users without the complexity traditionally associated with the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot App Focus on Usability and Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary objective of the Polkadot app is to make blockchain technology accessible to the average user. &lt;strong&gt;The app features a user-friendly interface&lt;/strong&gt; that eliminates many of the traditional barriers to entry associated with blockchain. Unlike many Web3 wallets that require users to manage complex seed phrases and navigate technical jargon, the Polkadot app offers a streamlined experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, users are not immediately confronted with the need to input a seed phrase or manage a username and password upon setting up the app. Instead, the app is designed to “just work,” allowing users to engage with blockchain features without being overwhelmed by the technical aspects. The traditional elements, such as seed phrases, are still available but are tucked away for those who wish to access them, preserving both simplicity and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot App for Everyday Transactions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of the Polkadot app is its built-in wallet, which enables users to pay for items in stores, transfer funds to one another, and manage their digital assets with ease. The app supports a simple username system, making it easy for users to send and receive funds without needing to remember complex wallet addresses. This feature is particularly useful for those unfamiliar with blockchain, allowing them to engage with the technology in a manner similar to more traditional payment methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the app is designed to support microtransactions and peer-to-peer payments with minimal fees, leveraging &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s Asset Hub&lt;/strong&gt;. This makes the app particularly attractive in regions where stablecoins might be preferred over local currencies, offering a cost-effective way to transfer value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Features of the New Polkadot App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-Centric Design&lt;/strong&gt;: The Polkadot app is crafted with simplicity at its core. It eliminates the need for users to manage complex seed phrases, passwords, or long wallet addresses. Instead, it leverages modern cloud solutions, such as Apple and Google Cloud, to back up credentials securely. This ensures that users can easily recover their accounts without compromising on security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamlined Onboarding&lt;/strong&gt;: Onboarding new users into the Polkadot ecosystem has never been easier. The app allows users to register using simple, readable usernames. This eliminates the confusion of dealing with long, complex wallet addresses, making it easier for users to send and receive assets like DOT, USDT, and USDC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seamless Payments&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the most innovative features of the Polkadot app is its ability to facilitate payments in a simple and user-friendly manner. Users can make payments at over a million stores and websites across the United States, with plans to expand to more than 33 countries and add over 2,000 brands by the end of the year. This makes the Polkadot app one of the most versatile blockchain payment solutions available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cashback Incentives&lt;/strong&gt;: To encourage adoption and usage, the Polkadot app offers up to 20% cashback in DOT on every purchase. This cashback is funded by the brands users shop at, making it a compelling incentive for users to utilize the app for their everyday purchases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Staking&lt;/strong&gt;: Staking is an integral part of the Polkadot ecosystem, and the new app makes it easier than ever. Users can stake their DOT tokens with just one click, allowing them to earn staking rewards effortlessly. This feature is designed to be accessible to even those who are new to blockchain technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shareable Payment Links&lt;/strong&gt;: The Polkadot app also introduces a feature that allows users to send payment links via text, WhatsApp, or email. This is particularly useful in scenarios where the recipient does not have the app installed yet. With a single click, the recipient can claim the tokens, making the payment process frictionless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborative Development&lt;/strong&gt;: The Polkadot app is a result of a collaborative effort between several key players in the ecosystem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/parity-technologies/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parity Technologies&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;led the design and concept, while the development was handled by the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/nova-wallet/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NovaSama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The payment functionality is powered by Rays, a company specializing in innovative payment solutions. This collaboration ensures that the app is robust, secure, and aligned with the needs of the Polkadot community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ownership by the Community&lt;/strong&gt;: In a true testament to the decentralized nature of the Polkadot ecosystem, the new app will be collectively owned by Polkadot token holders. This is made possible through the newly established Polkadot Community Foundation, which is legally controlled by DOT holders. This structure ensures that the community has a say in the future development and direction of the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Integration for Wallets&lt;/strong&gt;: In addition to its standalone features, the Polkadot app is also designed to be integrated with other self-custodial wallets via a payment API. This allows any wallet within the Polkadot ecosystem to leverage the app’s payment functionality, further enhancing its utility and reach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember this?&lt;br&gt;It took longer than expected to finish design and get everything underway but this work was foundational for the new Polkadot Pay app we’re shipping this year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to know more &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/lbx8t9K3U0&quot;&gt;https://t.co/lbx8t9K3U0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Bird⭕ (@itsbirdo_) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/itsbirdo_/status/1818183166974120446?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 30, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Integrating Web3 into Everyday Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app’s design philosophy is not just about simplifying blockchain but also about seamlessly integrating it into users’ everyday lives. For example, Polkadot’s partnerships with Esports teams and other entertainment sectors provide unique opportunities to engage users through blockchain. Whether it’s claiming digital collectibles, participating in community activities, or using the app to make purchases in both physical and digital stores, the possibilities are vast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot app is more than just a wallet; it’s a gateway to a decentralized future where users have full control over their assets and data. As the app continues to evolve, there are plans to integrate more features that will further enhance user experience, making blockchain technology as intuitive and accessible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Polkadot App Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot app is set to launch in Q3 2024, with development already well underway. The app represents a significant milestone for the Polkadot ecosystem, making blockchain technology more accessible and practical for everyday use. With its focus on simplicity, security, and real-world applicability, the Polkadot app is poised to become a cornerstone in the broader adoption of blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the app continues to evolve, users can expect further enhancements and integrations that will make it even more powerful and user-friendly. The collaboration between Parity Technologies, NovaSama, and Rays, along with the active involvement of the Polkadot community, ensures that the app will remain at the cutting edge of blockchain innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new app is not just a tool for the technically savvy; it’s designed for everyone—from the blockchain enthusiast to the everyday user—offering a gateway into the Polkadot ecosystem and the world of decentralized finance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Introduction to the New Polkadot Ledger App!</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/introduction-to-the-new-polkadot-ledger-app/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/introduction-to-the-new-polkadot-ledger-app/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;has taken a significant step forward in enhancing user experience and security with the release of the new Polkadot Ledger app. As the most popular hardware wallet on the market, &lt;strong&gt;Ledger&lt;/strong&gt; has long been a trusted name in &lt;strong&gt;cryptocurrency asset management&lt;/strong&gt;, and this latest development further solidifies its standing within the Polkadot community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Unified Access to Polkadot’s Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/tech-talks/generic-ledger-app-verifiable-metadata-polkadot-sub0/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Ledger app&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;is its ability to provide unified access to assets across all parachains. This is a game-changer for users who have been grappling with the challenges posed by the diverse and complex Polkadot ecosystem. Previously, users needed to manage multiple applications to interact with different parachains, leading to a fragmented and often cumbersome experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new app, users can now access all parachain assets from a single interface, significantly simplifying the process. This unified access is particularly beneficial for those who are active across multiple parachains, as &lt;strong&gt;it reduces the need to switch between different applications&lt;/strong&gt;, thereby enhancing overall user experience (UX).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enhanced Security Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security remains a top priority for Polkadot users, and &lt;strong&gt;the new Ledger app addresses this with several key improvements&lt;/strong&gt;. While hardware wallets are inherently more secure than software alternatives, the new Polkadot Ledger app introduces additional security enhancements. These improvements ensure that users can manage their assets with greater peace of mind, knowing that their funds are protected by the latest in security technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Integration with Leading Wallets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot Ledger app is designed to be versatile, offering compatibility with several leading wallets. Users can connect the app with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/talisman-wallet/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talisman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/subwallet/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SubWallet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/nova-wallet/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nova Wallet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and soon, &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot JS&lt;/strong&gt;. This wide range of integrations ensures that users can continue to use their preferred wallets while benefiting from the added security and convenience of the Ledger app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implications for the Polkadot Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release of the Polkadot Ledger app represents a significant milestone in the evolution of the Polkadot ecosystem. By addressing the long-standing issues related to &lt;strong&gt;UX&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and security&lt;/strong&gt;, the app is likely to encourage &lt;strong&gt;broader adoption of Polkadot’s parachain architecture&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, it underscores the ecosystem’s commitment to providing users with the tools they need to manage their assets securely and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YKNiAlHBwCg?si=hvxNTurSM_-NnPQ2&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Ledger app&lt;/strong&gt; is a crucial development for both the Polkadot community and the broader cryptocurrency space. By offering unified access to parachain assets, enhancing security, and integrating with leading wallets, the app sets a new standard for hardware wallet functionality. As Polkadot continues to grow and evolve, tools like the Ledger app will play a pivotal role in ensuring that users can navigate the ecosystem with confidence and ease.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>tech</category></item><item><title>Lionel Messi x Polkadot DAO Blockchain Marketing</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/lionel-messi-polkadot-dao-blockchain-marketing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/lionel-messi-polkadot-dao-blockchain-marketing/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking partnership, &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot DAO has officially confirmed its sponsorship of the Inter Miami football team&lt;/strong&gt;, where Lionel Messi, one of the most iconic footballers in history, currently plays. This collaboration marks a significant milestone, not just for Polkadot but for the entire blockchain industry, as it bridges the gap between decentralized technologies and mainstream sports culture, since this decision was entirely made by the Polkadot DAO through its network on-chain governance system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Significance of the Sponsorship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsorships in sports are nothing new; they have been a cornerstone of brand marketing for decades. However, the Polkadot DAO’s decision to sponsor Inter Miami, particularly as the primary sponsor for the team’s training gear, is a strategic move that signals the DAO’s ambition to expand its reach and &lt;strong&gt;visibility far beyond the usual crypto and blockchain circles&lt;/strong&gt;. By aligning with a globally recognized figure like Lionel Messi, Polkadot DAO is leveraging the star power of one of the most famous athletes in the world to enhance its brand recognition and credibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Messi and Inter Miami?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of Inter Miami, a relatively new team in Major League Soccer (MLS) but one that has gained enormous traction due to Messi’s involvement, is a calculated one. &lt;strong&gt;Messi’s transfer to Inter Miami in 2023&lt;/strong&gt; brought unprecedented attention to the team, making it an attractive platform for global brands. For Polkadot, this sponsorship is more than just a branding exercise; it’s a statement of intent to position itself at the forefront of the blockchain revolution for the USA market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/new-polkadot-logo-web-rebranding/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s new logo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;now emblazoned on the training kits of Inter Miami players&lt;/strong&gt;, including Messi, is not just a visual cue but a symbol of the merging of two seemingly disparate worlds—blockchain technology and global sports entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The New Polkadot Logo: A Subtle Yet Significant Change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting detail of this partnership, which has not been widely discussed, is &lt;strong&gt;the use of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/new-polkadot-logo-web-rebranding/&quot;&gt;new Polkadot logo&lt;/a&gt; on the Inter Miami training kits&lt;/strong&gt;. The updated logo is a slight variation from the original, with subtle changes to the typography that reflect the brand’s evolution while maintaining its core identity. This rebranding, while not drastic, is significant in that it represents Polkadot’s continuous adaptation and growth in a rapidly changing digital landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new logo’s debut on such a high-profile stage as Inter Miami’s training sessions, where it will be seen by millions of fans around the world, is a strategic move by Polkadot DAO to refresh its image while maintaining brand recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Impact of Rebranding on Polkadot’s Ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebranding is always a risk, particularly for a brand as established as Polkadot within the blockchain community. However, by introducing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/news/new-polkadot-logo-web-rebranding/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;new Polkadot logo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in conjunction with a major sponsorship deal, Polkadot DAO is ensuring that the rebrand is received positively and associated with high-profile, aspirational imagery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new logo’s introduction at a time when it will be seen alongside Lionel Messi—arguably one of the most marketable athletes on the planet—ensures that the rebranding is immediately linked with success, ambition, and global recognition. This can only bode well for Polkadot’s standing within the blockchain community and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot Marketing Strategy Traditional Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot’s sponsorship of Inter Miami represents a somewhat traditional marketing strategy in the context of blockchain, an industry that often leans heavily on digital and content-driven approaches. By opting for a sponsorship deal—a method more commonly associated with consumer brands and mainstream products—&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot is signaling a willingness to engage with audiences outside the typical blockchain community&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Inbound Marketing &amp;amp; Awarnes thorugh Sponsorships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, Polkadot has focused on inbound marketing strategies, such as content creation, education, and documentation, to build its brand and community. These strategies have been effective in attracting developers, builders, and early adopters within the blockchain space. However, the sponsorship of Inter Miami represents a shift towards a more outbound, awareness-focused approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;strong&gt;inbound marketing remains crucial for engaging with the core &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;Polkadot community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the sponsorship is designed to create &lt;strong&gt;broader brand awareness&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly in markets where blockchain technology is still gaining traction. The goal is not necessarily to convert Inter Miami fans into Polkadot users overnight, but rather to plant the seed of brand recognition that could pay dividends in the future as blockchain adoption grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Messi as a Brand Ambassador: The Broader Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messi’s association with Polkadot, even if indirect, carries significant weight. As a global icon, Messi’s endorsement—or even just his association with a brand—can have far-reaching effects. While Messi has not been formally named a brand ambassador for Polkadot, his wearing of the Polkadot-branded training gear effectively places him in that role, even if only passively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Potential Impact on Brand Perception&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Polkadot, this association is invaluable. Messi’s image, synonymous with excellence, sportsmanship, and success, could positively influence perceptions of Polkadot, especially among those who may not be familiar with blockchain technology. This association has the potential to elevate Polkadot’s brand from being seen as a niche technology to a little bit more mainstream player in the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Messi’s involvement could help to &lt;strong&gt;humanize and demystify blockchain technology for the average consumer&lt;/strong&gt;, making it more accessible and less intimidating. This could be particularly important in the United States, where blockchain adoption is still in its early stages compared to other regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Reactions and the Debate on Sponsorship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any major marketing move, Polkadot’s sponsorship of Inter Miami has sparked debate within its community. Some members are enthusiastic about the partnership, seeing it as a bold and necessary step to increase Polkadot’s visibility. Others, however, are more skeptical, questioning whether this traditional marketing approach aligns with Polkadot’s values and long-term goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skepticism and Support: A Divided Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critics within the Polkadot community argue that the sponsorship might not yield the desired results, as the primary audience for blockchain technology—developers and early adopters—may not overlap significantly with football fans. They also express concerns that the funds used for the sponsorship could have been better allocated towards development initiatives, community grants, or other ecosystem-building activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messi now wears Polkadot when he trains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what did it cost and how does it compare to previous deals–OKX, Crypto(dot)com, Tezos, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i only used publicly available information from press releases. i ignored deals with undisclosed financial details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter Miami &amp;amp; Polkadot -… &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/8AAcHnq59z&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/8AAcHnq59z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— gbaci (@gbaciX) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gbaciX/status/1830944354929643610?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 3, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Supporters, on the other hand, believe that the sponsorship is a smart move that will help Polkadot break out of the blockchain echo chamber and &lt;strong&gt;reach new audiences&lt;/strong&gt;. They argue that &lt;strong&gt;brand recognition and awareness are crucial for the long-term success&lt;/strong&gt; of any technology platform, and that this sponsorship is a strategic investment in Polkadot’s future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Role of Polkadot Governance in Decision-Making&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the interesting aspects of this sponsorship is how it reflects the governance model within the Polkadot ecosystem. As a decentralized autonomous organization (DAO), &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s decisions are driven by community input and governance votes&lt;/strong&gt;. This sponsorship deal likely went through several layers of discussion and approval within the community, reflecting the DAO’s commitment to transparency and collective decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate surrounding the sponsorship also highlights the importance of governance in balancing different perspectives within the community. While some members may prioritize technical development, others may see value in broader marketing initiatives. The ability to navigate these differing viewpoints is a testament to the strength and flexibility of Polkadot’s governance model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Future: What This Means for Polkadot and the Blockchain Industry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot DAO’s sponsorship of Inter Miami is a bold and unconventional move that could have significant implications for both Polkadot and the broader blockchain industry. By associating with a global icon like Messi and a high-profile sports team, Polkadot is taking a calculated risk that &lt;strong&gt;could pay off in terms of brand recognition&lt;/strong&gt; and market expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Potential Ripple Effects in the Blockchain Space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This partnership could set a precedent for other blockchain projects to explore similar sponsorship deals, particularly as the industry continues to seek ways to enter the mainstream consciousness. If successful, the Polkadot-Inter Miami sponsorship could pave the way for more collaborations between blockchain companies and mainstream brands, further blurring the lines between the digital and physical worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, this sponsorship could also spark a broader discussion within the blockchain community about the role of traditional marketing strategies in a digital-first industry. As blockchain technology matures and seeks wider adoption, the industry may increasingly turn to established marketing practices to reach new audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion: A Strategic Gamble with High Stakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot’s sponsorship of Inter Miami and the association with Lionel Messi is a strategic gamble that reflects both ambition and innovation. While it remains to be seen whether this sponsorship will achieve its desired outcomes, it undeniably marks a new chapter in Polkadot’s journey and the evolution of blockchain marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world watches Messi don the Polkadot-branded training gear, the blockchain community will be keenly observing how this partnership unfolds and what it means for the future of both Polkadot and the broader industry. Whether a masterstroke or a misstep, this sponsorship is a testament to Polkadot’s willingness to push boundaries and explore new frontiers in its quest to become a leading player in the decentralized digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>marketing</category></item><item><title>New Polkadot Education App for Beginners!</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/new-polkadot-education-app/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/new-polkadot-education-app/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Polkadot, known for its innovative approach to interoperability and decentralized networks, &lt;strong&gt;and also for its complexity&lt;/strong&gt;, has always been at the forefront of blockchain advancements. Now, with the &lt;strong&gt;introduction of a new Polkadot education app&lt;/strong&gt;, the ecosystem is making more strides in educating the next generation of blockchain enthusiasts and professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Polkadot Learning Platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Polkadot education app is designed to cater to a wide range of users, &lt;strong&gt;from beginners to seasoned professionals&lt;/strong&gt;. The platform offers a comprehensive course that covers everything from the fundamentals of blockchain technology to advanced applications within the Polkadot ecosystem. This ensures that users at all levels can benefit from the content, gaining the knowledge and skills needed to excel in the blockchain space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain Fundamentals:&lt;/strong&gt; The course begins with a deep dive into the basics of blockchain, explaining the underlying technology, its structure, and its basic functioning. This section is crucial for beginners who need to understand the foundation upon which all blockchain applications are built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Polkadot:&lt;/strong&gt; For those looking to specialize in Polkadot, the app offers an extensive exploration of the platform. Users will learn about Polkadot’s unique features, such as its ability to facilitate interoperability between different blockchains, making it a standout in the blockchain industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security and Consensus Mechanisms:&lt;/strong&gt; As security is a paramount concern in any decentralized environment, the app delves into the essential security and consensus mechanisms that ensure the reliability and integrity of blockchain transactions. This section is particularly valuable for developers and technical users who need to understand how to build secure applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical Use Cases:&lt;/strong&gt; The app also provides real-world case studies demonstrating how blockchain and Polkadot are being applied across various sectors, including finance, healthcare, and logistics. This practical approach helps users see the tangible benefits of blockchain technology and its potential for transforming industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Development:&lt;/strong&gt; For those with a technical background, the app offers in-depth modules on developing applications and smart contracts that are compatible with the Polkadot ecosystem. This section is designed to equip developers with the skills needed to build cutting-edge blockchain solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Perspectives:&lt;/strong&gt; The course concludes with a look at emerging trends and future possibilities within the blockchain and Polkadot ecosystems. This forward-thinking approach ensures that users are prepared for the innovations and opportunities that lie ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn about Polkadot from Anywhere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of this new education app is its accessibility. The platform is designed to be mobile-friendly, allowing users to learn from anywhere at any time. Whether you’re a business professional looking to explore blockchain’s potential or a developer aiming to build on Polkadot, this app offers the flexibility to learn at your own pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who Is It For the App Polkadot Education?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Polkadot education app is tailored to meet the needs of various user groups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Business Users:&lt;/strong&gt; The app provides insights into the benefits of blockchain for businesses, including operational efficiency, transparency, and cost reduction. It also explores specific Polkadot use cases across industries such as finance, healthcare, and logistics, offering strategies for integrating blockchain into existing processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Technical Users:&lt;/strong&gt; Technical users will benefit from an in-depth analysis of Polkadot’s architecture, including parachains, relays, and the consensus layer. The app also focuses on developing the technical skills needed to build applications within the Polkadot ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Beginners:&lt;/strong&gt; Even those new to blockchain will find the app accessible, with clear explanations of blockchain concepts and their impact on everyday life. Beginners will also learn about Polkadot’s potential for enhancing security, privacy, and inclusion, as well as how to participate in Polkadot-based projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-12008&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_12008&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px&quot;&gt;![easya App Polkadot education](../../uploads/2024/08/easya-App.webp)&lt;figcaption class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot; id=&quot;caption-attachment-12008&quot;&gt;easya App Polkadot education&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Role of EasyA in Polkadot Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the new Polkadot education app, &lt;strong&gt;EasyA&lt;/strong&gt;, a well-known education platform active in the Polkadot ecosystem, has played a significant role in blockchain education over the past few months. EasyA has been instrumental in spreading knowledge about Polkadot, offering courses and resources that complement the new app. Together, these platforms are setting a new standard for blockchain education, ensuring that users are well-equipped to navigate the complexities of the decentralized world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Polkadot Education Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the new Polkadot education app marks a significant milestone in blockchain education. By providing a comprehensive, user-friendly platform, Polkadot is not only educating the next generation of blockchain professionals but also empowering users to leverage the full potential of the Polkadot ecosystem. Whether you’re a business leader, developer, or newcomer to blockchain, this app offers the tools and knowledge you need to succeed in the rapidly evolving digital landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the blockchain space continues to grow, the importance of education cannot be overstated. With resources like the Polkadot education app and EasyA, users are well-positioned to lead the next digital era, driving innovation and transformation across industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information and to get started on your blockchain learning journey, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polkadot.education/en&quot;&gt;Polkadot Education&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.easya.io/&quot;&gt;EasyA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for more advanced adventurers, you can find the next steps on platforms and initiatives like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/polkadot-blockchain-academy/&quot;&gt;Polkadot Blockchain Academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dotcodeschool.com/&quot;&gt;DotCodeSchool&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://polkadot.study/&quot;&gt;Polkadot.Study&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>education</category></item><item><title>New Polkadot Head Ambassador Role and its $10,000 Salary</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/new-polkadot-head-ambassador-role-and-its-10000-salary/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/new-polkadot-head-ambassador-role-and-its-10000-salary/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; continues to evolve with the introduction of the new &lt;em&gt;“Head Ambassador”&lt;/em&gt; role, a pivotal position aimed at enhancing &lt;strong&gt;business development&lt;/strong&gt; within the network. This new initiative has sparked considerable discussion within the Polkadot community, especially as the governance of the network becomes increasingly dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Increased Activity in Polkadot’s Governance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent months, the &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot governance system, known as OpenGov&lt;/strong&gt;, has witnessed an unprecedented surge in activity. The average number of daily proposals has climbed to four, reflecting a heightened engagement from the community. This uptick in activity has had a noticeable impact on the Polkadot Treasury, which has seen funds being allocated at a rapid pace. Consequently, there is growing advocacy for the promotion of low-budget, independent proposals, particularly those from creators who are more grassroots and indie in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of Polkadot Head Ambassadors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Head Ambassador role is a new and significant addition to the Polkadot governance framework. This position is closely linked to the ongoing Fellowship program, which is transitioning from the original Ambassador program to a more organized, on-chain structure. The community now has the power to vote on who will assume the Head Ambassador role, making it a more dynamic position compared to its predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary function of Head Ambassadors will focus on business development, playing a crucial role in advancing the network’s interests. The selection process for these positions has already begun, with several candidates from the Polkadot community, including those from the Spanish-speaking sector, vying for the role. Notable candidates include figures like Limo and Max Rewall, who have been nominated by community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community and Governance Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the Head Ambassador role has prompted discussions within the community regarding the qualifications and responsibilities of candidates. There is a debate on whether these ambassadors should possess technical expertise and to what extent. Furthermore, community members like Sassenberg from the “Voces Descentralizadas” (Decentralized Voices) delegation have emphasized the importance of transparency from candidates, particularly concerning their schedules and commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A notable aspect of the Head Ambassador role is the compensation, set at &lt;strong&gt;$10,000 per month&lt;/strong&gt;. This salary reflects the high expectations placed on these ambassadors, who are expected to be highly active and engaged in their duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fellowship Track and Future Prospects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fellowship track on Subsquare has become the primary platform where community members can observe and evaluate the candidates for the Head Ambassador role. This transition is part of a broader movement towards on-chain governance, with the community playing a more active role in shaping the direction of the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web3 Foundation has also published a comprehensive review of the first cohort of the “Voces Descentralizadas” program, which provides insights into the performance and voting patterns of delegates. This report highlights the importance of active participation and alignment among delegates, with ChaosDAO emerging as one of the most active participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9B2o7oTaMWQ?si=pXET67roRiNXelXU&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the Head Ambassador role represents a significant step forward in the evolution of Polkadot’s governance and business development strategies. As the network continues to grow, these ambassadors will play a crucial role in shaping its future, ensuring that Polkadot remains at the forefront of innovation in the blockchain space. The community will be closely watching how this new role develops and what impact it will have on the broader ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>governance</category></item><item><title>New Polkadot Logo and Web Rebranding!</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/new-polkadot-logo-web-rebranding/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/new-polkadot-logo-web-rebranding/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Polkadot has recently undergone a significant rebranding, marked by the unveiling of a new logo and the migration to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://polkadot.com&quot;&gt;Polkadot.com domain&lt;/a&gt;. This initiative, spearheaded by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/distractive-agency/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distractive team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, represents a bold step forward for the network. However, as with any major change, it has sparked a range of reactions within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Polkadot Rebranding: Website and Domain Migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rebranding of Polkadot is not limited to the introduction of a new logo; it also includes a comprehensive update of its online presence. The migration to the Polkadot.com domain signifies a strategic shift designed to enhance the network’s visibility and accessibility. After eight years of using the previous domain, this move underscores Polkadot’s commitment to growth and adaptation in an ever-evolving digital landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new website, which accompanies the domain migration, features a &lt;strong&gt;refreshed design&lt;/strong&gt; that aligns with the sleek aesthetics of the new logo. This cohesive visual identity is intended to &lt;strong&gt;present Polkadot as a modern, dynamic, and forward-thinking ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, appealing to both new users and seasoned blockchain enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‼️ATTENTION‼️&lt;br&gt;MARTIAL ARTS CONFRONTATION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I want to compare the logo proposed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/distractivexyz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@distractivexyz&lt;/a&gt; and the current &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Polkadot?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@Polkadot&lt;/a&gt; logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I know that as a Polkadot community we have more urgent problems to solve right now, like the problem of high inflation or the problem… &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/DWK7cyy5XU&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/DWK7cyy5XU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Dariusz Szustakowski (@SzuDar91) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SzuDar91/status/1831263818443334000?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 4, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Community Feedback: Praise and Concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the new logo and rebranding efforts have been generally well-received, not all feedback has been positive. Many in the community have praised the new design for its simplicity and modern appeal, seeing it as a fitting representation of Polkadot’s innovative spirit. However, some have expressed &lt;strong&gt;concerns about the decision-making process behind the logo redesign&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key points of contention is the lack of public consultation through the network’s governance process. &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot, known for its decentralized governance model, typically involves its community in major decision&lt;/strong&gt;s. The absence of a public vote or consultation before the rebranding has left some community members feeling excluded from a decision they believe should have been collective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to concerns about governance, &lt;strong&gt;there are mixed opinions regarding the impact of the domain migration&lt;/strong&gt;. After eight years with the previous domain, the shift to Polkadot.com has raised questions about the potential risks and benefits. Some fear that the change could &lt;strong&gt;disrupt the search engine visibility&lt;/strong&gt;, while others believe it is a necessary step for Polkadot to assert its position in the broader blockchain industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-12871&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_12871&quot; style=&quot;width: 698px&quot;&gt;![polkadot new website](../../uploads/2024/09/polkadot-new-website.webp)&lt;figcaption class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot; id=&quot;caption-attachment-12871&quot;&gt;[polkadot new website](//polkadot.com/)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Complex Implications of the Polkadot Rebranding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebranding and domain migration are not without their complexities. While they can provide a fresh start and new opportunities, they also carry risks, especially in an established ecosystem like Polkadot’s. The true impact of these changes on the network’s development remains to be seen, and it is too early to draw definitive conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the effects of the rebranding efforts unfold, the community and industry observers alike will be closely monitoring the outcomes. The Distractive team’s role in managing this transition will be critical, as will the response from both the Polkadot community and the broader blockchain space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Polkadot Brand Kit Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those looking to incorporate the new Polkadot logo into their projects and publications, t&lt;strong&gt;he &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/distractive-agency/&quot;&gt;Distractive team&lt;/a&gt; has organized a comprehensive set of Polkadot brand resources&lt;/strong&gt;. These assets are available to ensure that the logo is used consistently and effectively across various platforms. Whether you are a developer, content creator, or community member, these resources will help you align with the new Polkadot branding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://file.notion.so/f/f/27a269ca-e1b1-4610-9298-76fc93cdb633/f4412a13-e830-42a4-969c-e3513916edb7/pd_brand_colors.pdf?table=block&amp;id=0af54ad6-172b-408c-b5d8-94cabe6b5474&amp;spaceId=27a269ca-e1b1-4610-9298-76fc93cdb633&amp;expirationTimestamp=1725343200000&amp;signature=zj5hd9n9kU36kwuDFcLV3Pe0imnW-FWKXQycLD0TUGU&amp;downloadName=pd_brand_colors.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Brand Colors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://distractive.notion.site/Polkadot-Brand-Kit-df6eda0f66df453ba6f7d2712f30d036&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Brand Kit (New Logo files)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot’s new logo and the accompanying rebranding efforts mark a significant moment in the network’s history. While the changes have been met with both praise and criticism, they undeniably represent a &lt;strong&gt;strategic effort to position Polkadot for continued success&lt;/strong&gt;. The impact of these changes will become clearer over time, and as they do, DaBlock.com will continue to provide in-depth analysis and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content:encoded><category>marketing</category></item><item><title>Searching for Proactive Polkadot Ecosystem Agents</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/opengov-direction-proactive-polkadot-ecosystem-agents/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/opengov-direction-proactive-polkadot-ecosystem-agents/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is experiencing a pivotal moment as OpenGov, the network’s decentralized governance model, gains increased attention and scrutiny. While recent discussions have often focused on the challenges and potential restructuring of the system, it is essential to emphasize actionable strategies that empower individuals to contribute meaningfully to the network’s growth. This article explores the current landscape of OpenGov and highlights &lt;strong&gt;opportunities for entry-level agents to make a tangible impact&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Evolution of OpenGov in Polkadot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenGov represents Polkadot’s commitment to a truly decentralized and participatory governance model. By &lt;strong&gt;allowing stakeholders to directly influence the network’s decision-making processes&lt;/strong&gt;, OpenGov ensures that the ecosystem evolves in a way that reflects the collective will of its community. However, as with any innovative system, OpenGov has faced its share of growing pains, leading to a surge in discussions about its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent conversations within the Polkadot community have often been dominated by complaints and suggestions for overhauling the system. While such discourse is a natural part of any evolving ecosystem, it is crucial to move beyond criticism and &lt;strong&gt;focus on constructive actions that drive progress&lt;/strong&gt;. This is where entry-level agents can play a vital role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic was raised at first&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/opengov-direction-for-entry-level-agents-get-up-and-get-moving/9340&quot;&gt; at the Polkadot Forum by the user Juba K&lt;/a&gt;, this article only tries to expand and make more accesible the original disccusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Importance of Accountability in OpenGov&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the key challenges within OpenGov is ensuring accountability&lt;/strong&gt;. As the number of proposals submitted to the governance system increases, so does the need for mechanisms that track and evaluate the impact of these initiatives. In response, several accountability frameworks have been developed, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/opengov-watch/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenGov.Watch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/og-tracker/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;OG Tracker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. These tools provide transparency by allowing the community to monitor the progress and outcomes of approved proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot governance forums&lt;/strong&gt; and platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/polkassembly/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkassembly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/subsquare/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SubSquare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have implemented updates to make proposal requirements more stringent and informative. By raising the bar for proposal submissions, these platforms help ensure that only well-considered and impactful initiatives are put forward, ultimately benefiting the entire ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shifting from Talk to Action: Opportunities for Entry-Level Agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;to thrive, it is essential to move beyond mere discussion and embrace a more action-oriented approach. This sentiment is echoed by ecosystem participants, who emphasize that real progress is achieved through tangible contributions rather than endless debates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entry-level agents within the Polkadot network are uniquely positioned to drive this shift&lt;/strong&gt;. By actively engaging in activities that promote the network’s growth, such as forming partnerships, promoting Polkadot’s value proposition, and contributing to the development of the ecosystem, these individuals can make a significant impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Examples of Proactive Engagement in the Polkadot Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several recent examples illustrate the potential for proactive engagement within the Polkadot ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avalanche DEX Reaching Out to Polkadot&lt;/strong&gt;: The collaboration between Avalanche and Polkadot demonstrates the value of cross-chain partnerships. By reaching out to other networks and establishing connections, entry-level agents can play a crucial role in expanding Polkadot’s influence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TokenTerminal’s Integration of a Polkadot Dataset&lt;/strong&gt;: The integration of Polkadot data by &lt;em&gt;TokenTerminal&lt;/em&gt; highlights the growing interest in Polkadot’s ecosystem. Entry-level agents can contribute by identifying and pursuing similar opportunities for collaboration and integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MapMetrics Moving to Peaq&lt;/strong&gt;: This example showcases the potential for projects to migrate to Polkadot or its related networks. By promoting the advantages of Polkadot, entry-level agents can encourage more projects to make similar moves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GrupoFlow Signing with Tanssii&lt;/strong&gt;: The partnership between GrupoFlow and Tanssii reflects the ongoing expansion of Polkadot’s ecosystem. Entry-level agents can facilitate such partnerships by reaching out to potential collaborators and showcasing the benefits of joining the Polkadot network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mythical Migration&lt;/strong&gt;: The collaboration between &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/mythos-chain/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mythical Games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot&lt;/strong&gt; is a prime example of how strategic partnerships can drive ecosystem growth. Entry-level agents can replicate this success by identifying and pursuing similar opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Seizing the Opportunity: The Role of Entry-Level Agents in OpenGov&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The current landscape of OpenGov presents a unique opportunity for entry-level agents to make their mark on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. With the recent focus on Treasury spending and the increased attention on governance activities, there has never been a better time to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking the initiative to engage with other networks, protocols, and projects, entry-level agents can contribute to Polkadot’s growth while also positioning themselves for future opportunities. Whether through cold calling, emailing, or setting up partnerships, the possibilities are endless for those willing to put in the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion: A Call to Action for the Polkadot Community&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of Polkadot’s OpenGov system depends on the collective efforts of its community. While discussions and debates are a natural part of the governance process, it is crucial to transition from talk to action. Entry-level agents have a unique opportunity to contribute to the ecosystem’s growth by actively engaging in activities that drive progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Polkadot community continues to evolve, &lt;strong&gt;the role of entry-level agents will become increasingly important&lt;/strong&gt;. By taking proactive steps to promote and expand the network, these individuals can help shape the future of OpenGov and ensure that Polkadot remains at the forefront of the blockchain industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the discussion in the&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.polkadot.network/t/opengov-direction-for-entry-level-agents-get-up-and-get-moving/9340&quot;&gt; original forum post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content:encoded><category>governance</category></item><item><title>PoKe Initiative for Polkadot Enterprise Adoption</title><link>https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/poke-initiative-for-polkadot-enterprise-and-government-adoption/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dot-news-six.vercel.app/pt/news/poke-initiative-for-polkadot-enterprise-and-government-adoption/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In an era where blockchain technology is increasingly recognized as a transformative force across industries, Polkadot stands out as a robust and versatile ecosystem tailored for large-scale adoption. To further cement its position as a leading blockchain infrastructure provider, Polkadot has launched a dedicated business development unit known as &lt;strong&gt;PoKe (Polkadot’s Key Account Unit)&lt;/strong&gt;. This initiative, driven by &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/scytale-digital/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scytale Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;BOTLabs GmbH&lt;/strong&gt;, focuses on introducing and onboarding large enterprises and government entities, particularly within Europe and the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PoKe Strategic Vision for Polkadot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoKe is poised to bridge the gap between Polkadot’s advanced blockchain technology and the specific needs of large institutions and governments. While Polkadot’s decentralized architecture is well-suited for fostering innovation and scalability, &lt;strong&gt;PoKe aims to highlight its exceptional suitability for institutional use cases&lt;/strong&gt;. The initiative is not just about promoting the technology but ensuring its adoption through tailored business development efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Key Unit Players and Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scytale Digital and BOTLabs GmbH, the entities spearheading PoKe, bring a wealth of experience and deep ties within the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. BOTLabs GmbH, notably known for its development of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/dapps/kilt-protocol/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KILT Protocol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is a veteran in the blockchain space, and its collaboration with Scytale Digital underlines the initiative’s commitment to leveraging Polkadot’s potential for institutional and governmental applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoKe’s mission is to actively engage with decision-makers in corporations and governments, demonstrating how Polkadot’s blockchain solutions can address real-world challenges. This approach marks a shift from traditional blockchain outreach, which often focuses on developers and smaller projects, to a more strategic engagement with key institutional stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Role of Web3 Foundation &amp;amp; Decentralized Futures Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/web3-foundation/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3 Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a significant supporter of the Polkadot ecosystem, funds PoKe under its &lt;strong&gt;Decentralized Futures program&lt;/strong&gt;. This program is designed to support initiatives that drive the growth and decentralization of Polkadot by fostering the development of new teams and entities within the ecosystem. By backing PoKe, the Web3 Foundation emphasizes its commitment to scaling Polkadot’s impact on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polkadot Key Unit Outreach and Engagement Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoKe’s strategy includes participating in &lt;strong&gt;industry-specific conferences, policy discussions, and high-profile events&lt;/strong&gt; where blockchain’s potential is a central theme. This focused engagement ensures that Polkadot’s capabilities are highlighted in contexts where they are most relevant, such as in discussions on digital identity, data sovereignty, and secure infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, PoKe plans to expand its outreach beyond general blockchain events, targeting vertical-specific conferences where the unique features of Polkadot can be showcased to potential adopters within industries such as finance, healthcare, and public administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tqUFLTDcgMg?si=OGzVD2Axr9p9RKZ0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poke &amp;amp; Polkadot’s Institutional Adoption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadot is already recognized as a leading blockchain platform &lt;strong&gt;with substantial institutional adoption&lt;/strong&gt;. Unlike other blockchain networks primarily associated with only decentralized finance (DeFi), &lt;strong&gt;Polkadot’s architecture is designed for scalability, interoperability, and security&lt;/strong&gt;, making it particularly attractive to enterprises and governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoKe’s initiative is a continuation of Polkadot’s ongoing efforts to establish itself as the blockchain of choice for large-scale, institutional-grade applications. By actively engaging with key stakeholders, &lt;strong&gt;PoKe aims to accelerate Polkadot’s adoption in critical sectors&lt;/strong&gt;, further positioning it as a cornerstone of the digital transformation across Europe and the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoKe represents a significant step in Polkadot’s journey toward becoming a dominant force in the blockchain industry. By focusing on business development and strategic engagements, PoKe aims to unlock new opportunities for Polkadot within the enterprise and government sectors. Backed by the expertise of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/scytale-digital/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scytale Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;BOTLabs GmbH&lt;/strong&gt;, and supported by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dablock.com/ecosystem/web3-foundation/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3 Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, PoKe is set to play a crucial role in driving Polkadot’s growth and adoption on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>business</category></item></channel></rss>